<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The town-shifts, or, The suburb-justice a comedy, as it is acted at His Royal Highness the Duke of York's theatre.</title>
            <author>Revet, Edward, fl. 1671.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1671</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 189 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 38 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A57098</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1194</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R635</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12241226</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12241226</idno>
            <idno type="VID">56777</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A57098)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 56777)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 875:54)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The town-shifts, or, The suburb-justice a comedy, as it is acted at His Royal Highness the Duke of York's theatre.</title>
                  <author>Revet, Edward, fl. 1671.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[6], 68, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Dring ... and William Cademan ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1671.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Epistle dedicatory signed: Edw. Revet.</note>
                  <note>Attributed to Edward Revet. cf. NUC pre-1956.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>English drama --  Restoration, 1660-1700.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-03</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE TOWN-SHIFTS, OR, THE Suburb-Juſtice: A COMEDY.</p>
            <p>As it is Acted at His Royal Highneſs the Duke of <hi>York</hi>'s Theatre.</p>
            <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <p>Licenſed, <hi>May</hi> 2. 1671.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Roger L'Eſtrange.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Dring,</hi> at the White Lyon next <hi>Chancery-Lane,</hi> in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet:</hi> And <hi>William Cademan,</hi> at the Pope's Head in the Lower Walk of the <hi>New-Exchange.</hi> 1671.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:2"/>
            <head>TO His Worthy, and Eſteemed good Friend, <hi>STEPHEN MOSEDELF,</hi> Eſquire.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He favours I have ſo frequently found from your continual kindneſs, is the occaſion I have taken the Confidence to kiſs your hand with this home<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Offer of my ſincere Services. I know your Ingenuity will eaſily diſcover thoſe im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perfections which your Generoſity will as quickly pardon. But leſt they ſhould come too faſt, and fall too heavy upon your pati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence, be pleaſed to take this truth as an allay. That it was thought on, begun, and finiſhed, in a fortnight: therefore unlike to appear ſo Correct, as in reaſonable expectation a Play
<pb facs="tcp:56777:3"/>ſhould be, before it paſſes Stage-proof. I muſt confeſs it a great defect of Judgment in me, and expect to be accuſed of much ir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rational Confidence, for committing this <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor</hi> to make its way through ſo large a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gregation of Criticks, as appear in the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution of all Plays. But tis with me, as with Animals, that boldly attempt ſwim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming, wanting reaſon to apprehend the wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter fatal: So I (without fear of Cenſorious Laſhes, which a wiſer Man might have expected to be the Concluſion of ſuch an Adventure) have plung'd my ſelf unawares into a mercileſs Sea of Satyriſts; which I fear will prove Fatal, if I find not protection under your Patronage.</p>
            <p>Which is the humble requeſt of,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Sir,</salute> 
               <signed>Your Obliged, and Obedient Servant, EDW. REVET.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="prologue">
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:3"/>
            <head>PROLOGUE.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>YOu are of late, Gallants, grown ſo ſevere,</l>
               <l>Plays on the Poſt are damn'd, before you hear:</l>
               <l>Why ſhould you be ſuch ſtrangers to remorſe,</l>
               <l>To Judge, before you try? The faireſt Courſe,</l>
               <l>Could we for once adviſe, would be to ſtay</l>
               <l>And hear the Cauſe, before you giv't away.</l>
               <l>But ſince 'tis ſo, we ſcorn to court a ſmile:</l>
               <l>Be cruel as you can, ſcoff, and revile</l>
               <l>Till you have ſpent your Spleens; that ſo you may</l>
               <l>Want them for to condemn a better Play.</l>
               <l>This may deſerve the worſt that you can ſay;</l>
               <l>Would the Judicious only Criticks be,</l>
               <l>They'd do't, where there's juſt cauſe, and moderately.</l>
               <l>But there's an up-ſtart Crew, a Generation</l>
               <l>Of little Fopps, Criticks by imitation:</l>
               <l>Young Men in Flaxen Wiggs, juſt ſent to Town,</l>
               <l>For to be cheated, and to wear a Gown.</l>
               <l>Theſe are the little things, perch't in the Pitt,</l>
               <l>Making of noiſes, which ſome Fools think wit:</l>
               <l>Cry down what is now, or what e're was writ.</l>
               <l>Be juſt for once, and grant me this demand;</l>
               <l>Let me be doom'd by thoſe that underſtand:</l>
               <l>Death Glorious looks, brought by a Noble hand.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="dramatis_personae">
            <pb facs="tcp:56777:4"/>
            <list>
               <head>Dramatis Perſonae.</head>
               <item>
                  <label>LOvewell,</label> Mr. <hi>Cademan.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Friendly,</label> Mr. <hi>Medbourn.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Faithfull,</label> Mr. <hi>Weſtwood.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Leftwell,</label> Mr. <hi>Angel.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Pett,</label> Mr. <hi>Norris.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Frump,</label> Mr. <hi>Sandford.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Stingey,</label> Mr. <hi>Sherwood.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Runwell,</label> Mr. <hi>Whaley.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Moſes,</label> Mr. <hi>Williams.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Conſtable, Watchmen, and Servants.</item>
               <item>
                  <label>Leticia,</label> Mrs. <hi>Lee.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Fickle,</label> Mrs. <hi>Long.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>Betty,</label> Mrs. <hi>Dixon.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <label>
                     <hi>Goody</hi> Fells.</label> Mrs. <hi>Norris.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Playes Printed for, and ſold by <hi>Thomas Dring.</hi>
               </head>
               <item>LOve and Honour.</item>
               <item>Unfortunate Lovers.</item>
               <item>Raſe a Wife, and have a Wife.</item>
               <item>Thierry and Theodoret.</item>
               <item>The Woman-Hater.</item>
               <item>The Changeling.</item>
               <item>Albumazar.</item>
               <item>School of Complements.</item>
               <item>Hero and Leander, Trag.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Playes now in the Preſs.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>The Amorous Prince.</item>
               <item>Six day's Adventure, or the <hi>New Utopia.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="play">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:56777:4"/>
            <head>THE Town-Shifts.</head>
            <div n="1" type="act">
               <head>Actus primus.</head>
               <div n="1" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena prima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, <hi>ſolus.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hanks to ill Fortune; I have liv'd long enough, and ſpent money enough, to make me poor in pocket, and rich in Experience; in which expence, both of time and money, I've learn'd there's nothing ſo great a fault, or leſs a Mans Friend, that deſires to live in a full For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune, than Honeſty. My loſſes at Dice have ſufficiently qualify'd me for an expert cheat in that confounded Calling. My Converſation with thoſe kind things, call'd Women, has very well enabled me to perform the gentile profeſſion of pimping, now, of all Vices, moſt in faſhion; and that bluſhing Fool Modeſty's ſo much my Enemy, that I want the confidence to wheadle a poor Taylor to take my raggs off, and new rigg me. Whilſt I had money, never came a Night, but I was Uſher'd home by half a dozen of the Sons of this ſinful Town, to lay me ſafe in my Lodging, but thoſe went with my Money. Yet, Sot that I am, peſter'd with an old faſhion'd Principle of Hone<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty, I muſt needs hate to do as I have been done by, though the Devil offers me an excellent opportunity in Young <hi>Leftwell,</hi> a Fellow
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:56777:5"/>newly come to a large Eſtate, got by his damn'd Father, by the fall of many a fair Family; who has ſcarce wit enough to be made the ſore-man of a Watch. Now, whether it be not Religion to work upon this Animal; faith I think —</p>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter to him,</hi> Friendly, <hi>and Faithful.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, how now, <hi>Ned,</hi> pining in poverty?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Or contriving a way to create new Clothes?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Or, art waiting here with a watry ſtomack, in expectation of an Apparition of Pork and Turnips? 'Sdeath, <hi>Ned,</hi> this is the worſt way of dyet the Devil could direct thee.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>You're merry, Gentlemen; you're merry. Sure, the Devil you ſpoke of, <hi>Friendly,</hi> has made you ſo; has he not got up in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to your Garret at St. <hi>Giles's,</hi> and bought your ſoul for a ſmall morſel of Money? Why, the <hi>Spaniſh</hi> three-pence I left with you could never produce this ſpirit. You're grown witty, and wanton; what, are you well lyned in the pocket? Come, let's ſee; piſh, never retreat; what a Raſcal are you, to rally thus!</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>If your deſign be to ſearch his pockets, prethee deſiſt; for, to my knowledge, they fell out of his Breeches a Moneth ago; and he could have ſpar'd nothing better, for he has had no employment for them this twelve moneth.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Pox of your Trumpeters face; muſt you undertake to talk with your plump countenance? I am a Rogue, if I have not ſeen a Butter-eating <hi>Dutchman,</hi> that has been drown'd nine dayes, appear like a trim Courtier, in compariſon of thee. Thou art a Fellow that wouldſt give thy Ears (for Money thou haſt none) to kiſs the hand of a Kitchin Wench, in hopes to find fat enough upon her fingers, to allay the fury of thy Stomack.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Leave labouring your little wits, and draw near, for I in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend you two to be of my Councel.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned, Ned,</hi> we have alwayes found your Counſel to be nothing but perſwaſions to poverty, what a bleſſed thing it is to live Honeſt, and be lowſie; that it is better to be lazy, and lack every thing, than work in the wayes of wickedneſs for wealth.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>The Rogue by chance has clapt upon a truth. 'Tis e'en ſo, <hi>Ned.</hi> We have fed ſo long upon your Divinity Lectures, that we have almoſt forgot to eat in earneſt, and have hardly Linnen enough left to harbour a Lowſe. Therefore we'le have no more on't,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:56777:5"/>dear <hi>Monſieur</hi> Melancholy; for my part, I'm reſolv'd to turn Hector, quarrel in the ſtreets with Drunkards, and ſo ſteal Hats and Perukes; and begin to believe it a very pious way of living; Ay, and 'tis very taking.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>And I'm reſolv'd to follow thee; either fight, filch, padd, or pimp; and no longer ſuffer under the horrid perſecutions of Poverty.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>So, fate you well, Sir; fare you well.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>If I thought you were ſuch wretched Raſcals as you are pain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully making appear, you ſhould e'en pine in your poverty, e're par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticipate in my pious, and I hope, profitable deſign; but I know yee better. You hear, Gentlemen, that Young <hi>Leftwell</hi> is come of Age, though not to Years of diſcretion. Do you believe it a ſin to bubble this abominable Brute out of a part of that ill got, and like to be worſe ſpent, Eſtate?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, <hi>Ned,</hi> I think none at all; but how to do it, will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire ſome time to conſider on't: I could make ſhift to do it with the Dye, but the Rogue has been ſo cautious of that from his Cradle, that he ſwounds at the ſight of them.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Then Drinking will do nothing; for a pint of Ale puts a Padlock upon his Pocket; and you may as well perſwade a Presbyte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rian Parſon to Charity, as him out of a penny; there's no way, but to unlock his leachery by the ſight of a fine ſoft Wench.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>O hang him, he was once in Love with his Uncle's Kitchin-Maid, and, (as he calls it) was croſt in his affection; and ever ſince, the Fool faints at the ſight of a Female.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>But good Clothes muſt firſt be thought on; for you know we three are at preſent (as a man may ſay) in a very thread-bare condition; which this Clod-pole hates worſe than an Old Alderman does Hunting. 'Tis certain we ſhall never be receiv'd in this garb. <hi>Ned,</hi> cannot you get the old confiding man, ſweet Mr. <hi>Sowell,</hi> to new ſuit us, in order to this deſign, with a large promiſe of ſudden ſatisfaction?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell, <hi>and his Man</hi> Moſes.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>See where the Aſſe comes, ſadled in ſilk. Let's all put on ſobriety, and ſalute him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Leftw.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Moſes,</hi> can you tye a ſhooe in the neweſt faſhion?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Moſes.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I tyed your Fathers a fore you were born, and (peace be with him) he never diſlik'd it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="4" facs="tcp:56777:6"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Leftw.</speaker>
                     <p>Come to, then, but have a care of my Corns, good <hi>Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes.</hi> How now, <hi>Ned,</hi> no new Clothes yet; I would you were finer, that you might be fitter for my Company.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I am ſorry, Sir, that my ill garb commands me from your good Company.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Leftw.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee <hi>Ned,</hi> what are theſe Tatter-demallions that attend thee? they look like men of the forlorn hope, with half their Clothes taken off by ſmall ſhot. 'Slife, there's one has a hole ſhot through his Hat.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Friends of mine, Sir; that you would honour in acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledging.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, your moſt humble Servant; I ſhould be proud to be bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter acquainted.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I don't know you, nor deſire to be better acquainted with you, till you get better Clothes on your back. There's you, and your Friend, would ſerve for a couple of Scare-crows, if you could get Credit for carriage into the Countrey. I'le plague that Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, when I was poor, he perſecuted me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Td's Death, <hi>Lovewell,</hi> I ſhall be conſtrain'd to kick him; I cannot hold.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>O, by all means do, and ſtarve for't.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> how long have you known theſe Raggamuffins?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, an't pleaſe you, Sir, about a dozen years.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Alwayes in the ſame Clothes, I warrant; for leſs time sould never have taken 'em into ſo many pieces. Do you ever lye with them? Are their Shirts any better than their Suits?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>You're too great a Tyrant. They are, I aſſure you, Sir, Gentlemen of a very antient Family.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>If their Family be as old as their Clothes, 'tis Antient indeed. God by'e, Gentlemen; if ever I ſee you again, I ſhall certainly dream of a Dung-hill. Come along, <hi>Moſes.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Left. Moſes.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>What a damn'd Rogue is this? he has abus'd us beyond bearing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Let him talk on; I find now what will do it. I'le ſtrait to ſerious <hi>Sowell,</hi> and ſollicite him to help us: Meet me about ſeven a Clock at the Old Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>Heavens bleſs thee with the ſpirit of effectual perſwaſion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Excunt Omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="scene">
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:56777:6"/>
                  <head>Scena Secunda.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leticia, Fickle, Betty, <hi>in a Garden.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Couſin <hi>Fickle,</hi> thou haſt ſome of the ſtrangeſt humours in thee, that ever Maid was mad withal. Thou never lik'ſt a dreſs above half an hour, nor a man more than half a day: Thou art a meer <hi>Proteus,</hi> and put'ſt thy ſelf into as many ſhapes. Thou haſt been this one day in ſix ſeveral dreſſes; and the laſt week lov'd, and hated, ſeven ſeveral Men. No body that knows thee believes thee any thing elſe but di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtracted. We ſhall have thee, e're long, fall out with Life, and dye for diverſion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>And thou art (Dear Coz.) as mad the other way; thou hadſt rather wear thy Clothes till they are mouldy, then give thy Maid the trouble of a new tyring. That garb and Gown you now go in, is as well known as the Church, and I believe you think it as durable; for <hi>Betty</hi> ſayes you never intend to change it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O fye; Madam, never truſt me, if ever I talked of your Ladyſhip at this unmannerly rate.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Let her run on, Wench; I'm certain ſhe'le be out of love with this way of talking quickly: I've a mind to ſee if ſhe can con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue a quarter of an hour in any one thing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Then, Couſin, thou art mad of one Man. Thou haſt lov'd a Fellow in foul Linnen (I think he's a Gentleman) but what then? thou haſt lov'd him almoſt half a year, which is a horrible thing to think on. But I am weary of the Garden; I'le go talk of State<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>affairs to my old Uncle. Good b'ye, Coz.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Fickle.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Go thy wayes, Mad-cap: I'le undertake, before my Father can turn about and talk two words, ſhe'le be weary of the firſt, and go to find new Company.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I vow, Madam, ſhe wearies me out of my little wits, to pin, and unpin Curles; to add, and diminiſh colour; to new place the Pendants: any, ſometimes at Noon day, to put on Coyfes and Pinners. I would to Heaven ſhe were well marryed, that I might not be peſter'd. But now I talk of Marriage, pray, Madam, when did you hear from Mr. <hi>Lovewell?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Not a great while; <hi>Betty,</hi> I'm afraid I muſt wear the Willow, I doubt he has left me; what think'ſt thou?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:56777:7"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Madam, I dare ſwear, he had rather loſe his Eyes. If that Man be not truly a Gentleman, there's no Gentility in being. 'Tis a thouſand pities he's poor: In ſpight of his low garb he will look like himſelf; I'le tell you, Madam, when I have light him down ſtairs, and I dare ſwear he has not had three ſhillings in his pocket, he has put half a Crown into my hand, when I was grieved to take it. 'Twere ſin, to doubt his Love.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> I doubt you'le prove my Rival; could you find in your heart to love him, if I ſhould leave him?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>If I could not, I wiſh I might dye a Maid; which would be much againſt my will, Madam.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Heark, does not ſome body knock at the Garden Gate? Go ſee who 'tis.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I go, Madam; I vow, I hope from my heart 'tis he.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I love him well; yet, if I marry him, I'm loſt; and left to languiſh in a life of loathed poverty, for he is poor. And 'tis becauſe he has a generous ſoul, he is ſo. My Father cannot hear of him with patience; for he had rather wed me to a Brute, with Money, than to the beſt of Men, that wants it. That Age ſhould ſo defective be in Reaſon; as to prefer this ſordid Dung-hill Earth before the beſt of Gallantry and worth.</p>
                     <stage>
                        <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell.</stage>
                     <p>But here he comes, and <hi>Betty</hi> gone; this Baggage never fails to leave him to all opportunities; but I'le act a Womans part, for once; I'le appear ſtrange, to try him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>My dear <hi>Leticia!</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Soft; Sir, you have been away ſo long, you have forgot your duty. I pityed you whilſt you knew Civility, and for that reaſon in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulg'd you; and thought to have perſwaded my Maid to Marry you, and got my Father to put you into a Farm, in hopes you would in a little time become a perfect Plough-man. Your miſ-behaviour now makes me believe now you have been one. And ſo good b'ye, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Madam, let me conjure you. —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Hold, Sir, no conjurations; if you have any thing to ſay, ſpeak ſoberly, and at diſtance: I find, allowing you too near addreſs, begets you confidence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Will not this poſture ſerve, as well as any?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Kneels.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I, truly, I think that beſt becomes you; now go on, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Then I proceed, and beg a knowledge of my Crimes; and why I find thoſe killing frowns; a Cloud on that fair face, which
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:56777:7"/>was alwayes wont to wear ſuch ſmiles as ſweetned all my ſorrows, and made me triumph in deſpight of tears. Have I done ill? tell me, that I may dye: 'Twere Villany, to live after a Crime commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted againſt you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter to them,</hi> Pett, <hi>her Father.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>How's this? Certainly, that Fellow believes my Daughter to be the Goddeſs <hi>Ceres,</hi> and he's begging bread. I'faith, I ſhall put you beſides your Petition. De'you hear, Sir; there's nothing for you, I can aſſure you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>We're both undone — My Father — what will you do?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Friend, what's your buſineſs here? A man would gueſs by your Clothes you ſhould have more kindneſs for your ſtockings, than to beg on your knees. 'Tis ten to one, whether ſhe had given you enough to have mended what you wore out in your worſhip. But heark you, Sir; I believe, by your face, you come to ſollicite her Love. Pray pack off, Sir, or I'le make my Cane walk about your Coxcomb.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, will you —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir. Pray me no prays; but be gone, or I ſhall remove you at a very unmannerly rate: Will you ſtir, Sir?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me intreat —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le ſpoil your entreaties, with a pox to you. Put this Fellow out of doors, and ſee him pumpt.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Sir, have a little pity of the poor Gentleman; being hard purſu'd by Bayliffs, he, to avoyd them, got over the Garden Wall; and fearful he had frighted me, when you came in, was earn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſtly asking pardon. Now, Sir, you know the full of his offence, I hope you will retract your Sentence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I thought 'twas ſome ſuch Run-away-Raſcal; no, he ſhan't be pumpt, but turn him out to the liberty of the Law; let him pay, or to Priſon, a Gods name; turn him out of doors there.</p>
                     <stage>
                        <hi>Exit</hi> Love.</stage>
                     <p>Come, Daughter, I hope in a ſhort time to have a Husband for you; in the mean while I ſhall keep you from ſuch Cattle as this; for I be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin to find this is but an excuſe, to hide this beggarly Fellow's kindneſs. Let me ever ſee you with him again, and you ſhall ee'ne to him for al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together, with as many tatters as he has; for I am reſolv'd to diſ-own you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="8" facs="tcp:56777:8"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, you know my affections hitherto have waited on your will, and ſhall do ſtill.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pet.</speaker>
                     <p>I wiſh they may; come in with me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena tertia.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter Goody</hi> Fells, Friendly, Faithful.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Morrow, Gentlemen; I ſuppoſe you think I can feed upon Faggot ſticks, or pay my Rent with Cheeſe parings; why, what do you mean, Gentlemen? What do you mean? Muſt I never have my Money? here is now ſeven ſhillings, for ſeven weeks lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and as much for dyet, and waſhing the little linnen you have, God knows; this is money in a poor Womans pocket, Gentlemen.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Land-lady, be mollified; let not your paſſion put you beſides your Reaſon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Talk not to me of Reaſon, wretch, as thou art; give me my Money, I'le make more than one know on't, elſe. Then there's that blundering Sot, your Companion, that ſtands ſneering, and ſays no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, could come and borrow Money of my Maid; I'le call her, to witneſs it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, what then, Beldame?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, 'tis very well; if Young Wenches muſt work to lend you their wages.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>You, Dame damnable, hold your bawling tongue, in the Devils name, and ceaſe dunning, or I'le draw it out of your Mouth as long as my Arm.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee hold thy idle prating; you muſt give better words, fore <hi>George</hi> we ſhall get no Dinner elſe to day. Come, Land-lady, let me perſwade you into peace; a little time will enable us to pay you all: I have a Bill of Exchange to receive a hundred pounds with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in ſix weeks, and it ſhall all wait upon thy Command, dear Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lady.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, you know, Gentlemen, I am as unwilling to ſpeak, as the Child unborn; but when I am forc'd to it, you muſt not take it ill. I want four ſhillings of my Quarters Rent for my Houſe, to make it up five and twenty; if you could but furniſh me with that, it would do me a mighty kindneſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Pox of your old, ugly, abominable — no more dunning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:56777:8"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>O you Rogue, I will ask for my own, when you are hang'd. Sirrah, han't I been fain to lend you my own Shift to wear, whilſt yours was waſht, to keep you from being lowſie? Don't you now weat my poor dead Husband's? I cannot ſpeak of him, without tears.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Weeps.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Poor Land-lady, lament no more; 'tis true, <hi>Will</hi> was an honeſt fellow, and one that liv'd in the fear, as a Man may ſay, and would drink off his quart, or two, of Ale, as quietly as a Quaker, upon another Mans coſt.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Mr. <hi>Friendly,</hi> you knew him. Don't you remember, when I ſold Fruit firſt, how he beat <hi>Chriſtopher Crab,</hi> the Coſter-mon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, for calling o'me Grundy; he would not let a Lamb wrong me: he us'd alwayes to call me his Monkey.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Ay, marry did he. But, Land-lady, I hear you have a Flitch of Bacon ſent you from <hi>Will</hi>'s Friends.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>That I have indeed, Mr. <hi>Friendly;</hi> and 'tis as good as ever was cut with Knife: And if you will pleaſe to come home at din<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner time, and eat a piece, with an Egg, you ſhall be very welcome. It may be done homely, but I'le warrant you cleanly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>By this light, Land-lady, I don't know a better Cook then thou art, in all Chriſtendom; and here's honeſt <hi>Tom</hi> has ſaid ſo a thouſand times.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>'Tis more your goodneſs, than my deſert, to ſay ſo, Sir. I hope, Mr. <hi>Faithfull,</hi> you'le take no notice of what I have ſaid.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>No notice in the World, Woman; get Dinner ready, wee'le come in time.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Excunt omnes, ſeverally.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quarta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leticia, Betty, <hi>at a diſtance.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>My Servant, I'me afraid, is ſomething ſolitary, where e're he is; he cannot chuſe but wonder what's his, fault; my Fathers coming in diſturb'd both him and me: but here I have a Letter ready writ ſhall ſatisfie how well I love him; and that my laſt anger onely was to trye him. How ſad a thing is Love, when it wants liberty? The Man I love is one that does deſerve as much as Man may do; but yet my Father ſays, he that wants Money, conſequently wants Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit. What ſhall I do in this extremity? Love anſwers thus; In having
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:56777:9"/>him, I live; in miſſing him, I dye; I muſt do <hi>Cupid</hi> Juſtice. — <hi>Betty.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I've work for you to do; and ſuch as you'le take kindly: can you find in your heart to carry this Letter to Mr. <hi>Lovewell?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Madam, not contentedly, if I thought it were not kind. Pray, Madam, Commiſerate the poor Gentleman: you have enough for your ſelf, and him, and twenty to attend you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I, but my Father loves him not ſo well as thou doſt. He'le not hear of him that has nothing anſwerable to my full fortune.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>May your Father go into another World then, and let him live no longer, to hinder the happineſs of two ſuch real Lovers.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Away, you Baggage, carry your Letter, and take this purſe; deſire him to pay it where I order'd him; then bring me word, how he takes the Intelligence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I am gone, Madam.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Thou active god of Love, preſcribe a way To make me happy in a Marriage day.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="5" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quinta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly, Faithful.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee ſtand farther off, thy breath ſtinks of Red-Herrings, enough to ſtifle a man. I'm ready to run mad; never was man ſo mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, what's the matter, man? Art clapt by ſome kind Companion? or does thy Conſcience accuſe thee of living too long honeſt?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Or, has <hi>Sewell</hi> given a ſad denial; ſo that there's no hopes of new Habit?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, though nothing you gueſs at is the cauſe of my diſconte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>; yet I can tell you that will trouble you; there's little hopes of your being tyred in new Trappings: you may live ſtill in your leather Linings, and increaſe in Cattel. <hi>Sewell</hi> proves inexo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable, as to you, though kind to me. Gentlemen, mine are making; 'tis very true, Gentlemen, I wiſh the caſe were your own; yet I have ſomething ſtill ſticks worſe upon my ſtomack. Prethee ſtand fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther off, thou'lt ſtifle me with thy breath.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Out upon you, for a fretful fopp; you have been trading
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:56777:9"/>with ſome three-half-penny Wench, that's ſweetned with a penny<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth of <hi>Pomatum,</hi> and now your Noſe allows nothing elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, <hi>Friendly,</hi> wilt thou tell me one thing?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, I will.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>But will you ſeriouſly?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>By this light, I will.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Did you drink to day after your Dinner?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>The Devil's in this Satyrical Fellow; he pretends to be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes melancholy, and then he's moſt maliciouſly abuſive.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Ha, ha, ha.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Our bus'neſs is like to be well carryed on between a couple of conceited Coxcombe. If you can live with laughting at one another, I would have you do nothing elſe; if otherwiſe, why don't we come to the buſineſs? Haſt thou perſwaded the Taylor to provide us Tackle?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, Gentlemen, I'le put you out of your pain. What de'e think he ſays?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>De'e call this putting people out of their pain, to ſet their brains upon the Rack to reade your dealings with a damn'd Taylor, that no body knows where to find beſides your ſelf. Prethee, be ſeri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous but one minute, and let's be ſatisfi'd</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why then I'le tell you. After I had taken a great deal of pains to find him, and inquired at every Houſe where they ſold a ſeal'd quart for two pence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, what then?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, then I miſt him. And I aſſure you, never ſaw him ſince I ſaw you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, you have taken a great deal of pains, and made a mighty buſtle, to bring forth nothing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le be hang'd if he has not been drunk ever ſince in a Chim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney corner, with ſome Weavers Wife, without <hi>More-Gate;</hi> and at laſt been beaten out by her Husband, and that makes him melancho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Mr. <hi>Lovewell;</hi> will you give me leave to ſpeak one word in private with you?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Pretty Mrs. <hi>Betty;</hi> I'le wait on you inſtantly. Pray, dear
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:56777:10"/>Friends, leave me now. At Night I'le meet you, and give you (I hope) a good account of all our concerns.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned, Ned,</hi> this won't do; this is a little unkind: you have had a ſhare in a Miſtreſs of mine, e're now. What need you make theſe pretences to put us off? We know your meaning, ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver mince the matter, man; ſhe is a very pretty Wench; I would I were with her where thou haſt been.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I faith, <hi>Franck,</hi> ſhe's very civil. Let me deſire you to lay aſide all thoughts to the contrary, and you ſhall command me any thing. Prethee leave me a little.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Don't believe him, <hi>Franck;</hi> he'l feign a hundred things to fobb us off: but if I ſtir without a ſhare in this prize, I'le be pegg'd to a poſt for boys to throw rotten Pears at. Remember, <hi>Ned,</hi> you would not leave me one Morning, when my Landreſs came to my Chamber.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I ſee you're engag'd. I'm ſorry I came at this unlucky time to trouble you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> I beg your pardon; I am but giving theſe two Bayliffs directions about a buſineſs that concerns me<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> I ſhall have done in a minute.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I have no more heart to go, than a Man has to play at Dice the day before he's to be hang'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me conjure you by all our Friendſhip, not to offer me this moſt unmannerly affront. You don't know what injury you do me. Dear Friends deſiſt, ſhe's one that waits upon a perſon of Quality, and a near relation of mine, and not of that ſtrain you take her; faith, ſhe e'ant.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>What a pox, ne're tell us this. I ha' known you my ſelf theſe dozen years, and never ſee any thing with you look like an ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt Woman; nor will believe this ſo, though thou ſwear it by the ſoul of thy dead Father. What an idle thing is this in you, to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwade people to things ſo improbable, that know the World as well as you do; To go tell us that a Wench, in this garb, would be ſent to a Gentlemans Chamber at this time o'th day, if there want a deſign to do—Fye, fye.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>What harm will it do you, <hi>Ned,</hi> to let us have a little li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty with this pretty piece of Woman's fleſh? She'le be as fit for you again to morrow, as e're ſhe was. You know we are both ſound.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Sir; I'le call ſome other time.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> I've but a little more to ſay now, and they'le
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:56777:10"/>be fully inform'd in my affairs. Gentlemen, either leave me, or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve to fight me; for I would not endure to be thus affronted by my Father. Have you forgot all Friendſhip?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>No, hang ye, I love you a little too well yet, to fight with you for a Whore; and ſo good buy to ye.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>'Tis very fine, that we have liv'd thus long, and muſt now be Hector'd out of a Wench: I ſhall be quit with you, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, your Servant; pray be careful in the bus'neſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>We ſhall take care to requite you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Ex.</hi> Friend Faithful.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Was ever man thus peſter'd by a couple of Puppys<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                        <stage>Aſide.</stage> Now, Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> I'm ſorry I have been conſtrain'd by the tyranny of bus'neſs, to make you ſtay thus long.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>If it were much longer, Sir, I ſhould not have believed it a trouble, ſince 'tis to ſerve you. For I think I have a Letter here comes laden with Love: if I thought it had not, ſome body elſe ſhould have been the Meſſenger for me; for I hate to be concern'd in any thing that may diminiſh the content of a Gentleman. This is the Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter; and this Money my Lady deſires you to pay where ſhe has ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> I acknowledge my ſelf much bound to you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Reads.</stage>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>SIR,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>
                           <hi>I Am ſorry my Father fell ſo unhappily upon us, that hinder'd my Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluſion, which I intended as kind as I began cruel; but however I ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear'd then, I am now as you have alwayes found me, that unhappy, but affectionately, Yours,</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>L. P. As you love me, receive what I have ſent you. </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <p>Moſt bleſſed tydings. Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> pray be pleas'd to pay my humble ſervice to your Lady; and let her know, I chearfully obey her Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands.</p>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I hope, Sir, ſhe has laid no more upon you then you are able to bear. Your obedient Servant, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Your humble Servant, Mrs. <hi>Betty.</hi>
                        <stage>
                           <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage> This comes kindly, and cuts off much of my care; for I find my Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs faithful, and here's Money to new-Clothe me, and my two Friends.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:56777:11"/>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <p>How now, <hi>Runwell;</hi> how doſt thou hold out? canſt thou not find in thy heart to eat?</p>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I believe I ſhould not run away from a piece of a Roaſted Horſe: but let hunger be hang'd, I defie it; feed, or faſt, I'le never leave you, while I live, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Here's Money for you; when you have dyn'd, ſtep to <hi>Sew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ell,</hi> the Taylor; bid him come to me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>By this hand, Sir, if he refuſe to come, I'le bring him on my back.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Now will I ſet <hi>Sewell</hi> to work for me and my ill-clad Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panions, who I am ſure have gratitude enough to take it kindly.
<q>
                           <l>Then, my young Squire, I'le try what may be done:</l>
                           <l>Where no game's plaid, there's nothing can be won.</l>
                        </q>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
                  <trailer>Finis Actus primi.</trailer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="act">
               <head>Actus Secundus.</head>
               <div n="1" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena prima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, Leticia, Fickle, Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>BY my troth, Girles, you ſpoyl your ſelves with lying ſo long a bed; it makes you look like a great-belly'd Woman that has loſt her longing. <hi>Betty,</hi> I think I muſt give you a Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion to bang 'em up.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I Vow, Sir, I think you muſt get ſome body elſe to beat me up too then; for the Young Ladies have ſpoyl't me, and made me ready to lye as long as they.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fickle.</speaker>
                     <p>Uncle, your Man has the worſt way of dreſſing you in the World; Sir, he alwayes puts your Ruff on one way. 'Tis an errant ſhame to ſee a Man ſo long in one faſhion, as you have been.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What, art thou mad, Coz? There is but one way of putting on a Ruff, unleſs you would have me wear the fore-part behind.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:56777:11"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Look here, Sir, is your Ruff ty'd as my Whisk is? Pray, Sir, let me tye it. I proteſt I'le lay twenty ſhillings I tye it better than Old <hi>Ralph</hi> has done.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I like it very well, good Couſin, if thou could'ſt like it to let it alone; no body has found fault with it this twenty years, beſides thee. But I know thou wilt never let me alone till thou haſt done it; therefore, prethee diſpatch me quickly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>She pulls off one of her Ribbons, and tyes it.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Did he receive it with ſuch joy?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Joy! He could have ſaid or done no more, had I come for to ſecure him of eternal happineſs hereafter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le be judg'd by all the World now, if it be'nt handſomer by a hundred times; it looks like any Cravat. I vow, Uncle, if my Aunt were alive again, ſhe would a new fall in love with you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, what haſt thou done, Couſin; tyed up my Ruff like a ſhatter'd-brain'd Boy with a Taſſel at my Chin? Prethee give me my Point again. A pox of your Cravats, you ſhall never dreſs me more, I'le aſſure you; here, <hi>Leticia,</hi> take it you, and tye my Ruff, and let her have her Ribbon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, ſay what you will; I'm certain the Ribbon becomes you better than the Point. <hi>Betty,</hi> how thy Hood ſits to day! I dare be whipt if thou didſt not dreſs thee without the Glaſs; and this Whish ſits all awry: ſtep up to my Cabinet, I'le lend you one of my lac'd ones.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I thank you, Madam; I had as liff wear this to day.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, do then. Uncle, pray when comes my Couſin <hi>Lett's</hi> Servant? I long to ſee him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>You'le be dreſſing of him as ſoon as e're he comes within the doors, I dare ſwear. But to ſatisfie you, the man that loves her, and whom ſhe muſt love (if ſhe loves me) I expect to be here this Morning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, is he Young, or Old?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, Young, very Young; newly come of Age.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Is he a handſom man, Sir?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Very handſom, I proteſt, Couſin.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Has he money enough?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I, my good Girle; he has more money than twenty of the Whip-Jacks of this Town, who walk about with a half-ſtarv'd foot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boy, that has faſted three dayes, and never eats, but when his Maſter treats a Wench.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:56777:12"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Indeed, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I, indeed, Couſin.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>She'le weary my Father out of his wits.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Is he good-natur'd, Sir?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I, truly; I believe the Man to be of a good principle, and will be kind to a Wife.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Did he ever learn to Dance, Uncle?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le anſwer thee no longer; thou begin'ſt to be very impetti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent, Coz.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Will you walk in the Gallery then, Sir?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Any where, ſo thou wilt promiſe me not to weary me with thy eternal rattle.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena ſecunda.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly, Faithfull, <hi>in their Gallantry.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, Gallants, move with Majeſty. And ſhew your ſelves to the moſt advantage that may be. <hi>Faithfull,</hi> you are always looking upon your ſhooe-ſtrings, like a Prentice upon an <hi>Eaſter</hi> Holy-day. Hold up your Head, and look handſomly; take your Gloves out of your pockets, and put them on your Hands. I'm afraid, if I ſhould take this Rogue into Company, I ſhould be troubled to teach him the way to take off his Hat.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Then the Raſcals Peruke never ſtands the right way; and he makes leggs ſo like a Logger-head, that it would be ſuppos'd we took him out of a Mill, where he had learnt to dance of a Malt-horſe; for there's not a ſtep that he takes in his new ſhooes, but up comes a ſtone in the pavement.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le undertake, ſhould he go into a Noble-mans Hall, he would ſtamp a row of black and white marble to pieces in leſs than half a minute: never Horſe had ſuch hoofs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>And then he's ſo great a Sloven, that by that time he has worn theſe Clothes but three dayes, they'le be lac'd with all manner of liquour, and as greaſie as his old ones are, that the Rats have, ſince he left them off, run away with.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Talk on, Gentlemen, talk on; Cloath me thus but once a
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:56777:12"/>Moneth, and I'le for ever allow you the ſame priviledge you now take of prating. Forgive me, dear Patron, for I cannot chooſe but laugh at you, and that idle fellow, as a couple of very impertinent fopps.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell, <hi>and</hi> Moſes.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> how doſt do, Boy? now I like thee; now thou look'ſt like thy ſelf. Faith, I was reſolv'd to find thee out, and to new-furniſh thee at my own charge; thou wilt not believe how ſad I have been e're ſince I ſaw thee laſt. Let me look round about thee; faith, 'tis mighty rich: prethee what did it ſtand thee in? If I can ſerve thee in any thing, as far as my ſmall Eſtate goes, 'tis all at thy Service, ſweet Rogue.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>And I'le try you, Sir, ſince you're in ſo good a humour.
<stage>Aſide.</stage> Sir, I aſſure you you'd do me an exraordinary kindneſs, if you could furniſh me and my two Friends with a hundred pounds, for two or three dayes, no longer.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Pox on him, I thought he would not have faſten'd; would my words were in again.</p>
                     <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                     <p>Faith, <hi>Ned,</hi> if it will do thee a kindneſs, I cannot tell how to deny it. Here 'tis, with all my heart.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Upon my Honour I'le ſee it ſafe return'd, and eſteem it a very great favour.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Sir, you have done us a very conſiderable kindneſs; and in requital, command me any thing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, if you — 'Slife, I ſhall be undone; I was going to offer him as much more, who would, certainly, have accepted it as the firſt.</p>
                     <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                     <p>Sir, I rejoyce I had it to ſerve you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I hope we ſhall live to be gratefull, and find a way to make you ſatisfaction for this more than ordinary favour.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, there needs none of this. But let me tell you one thing, without offence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>No exception, I aſſure you, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Then, faith, I think you become your fine Clothes the worſt of any man that ever wore ſuch.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I muſt confeſs, Sir, I want the way of wearing Clothes well. I can afford to let you prate now, but I'le make your purſe pay for't.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:56777:13"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> will you aſſiſt me in a deſign? Faith, I am going about to commit Matrimony. Will you help to make Love to my Miſtreſs? I'le aſſure you ſhe's the handſomeſt Woman within a hundred Mile of her; and a Man that has the way of giving good words may win her heart, as I am inform'd, for I never ſaw her.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>How do you know ſhe's ſo handſom, then?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, her Father ſayes ſo, and ſweats he'le ſwinge her, if ſhe refuſe to fall in Love with me, or likes any body elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>What need you have any help, then? Your buſineſs is done to your hand.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>That's true, Mr. <hi>Friendly;</hi> but I would fain have it done by fair means; and there's <hi>Ned Lovewell</hi> knows how to work upon a Woman at will. I would fain have him and you go to make up the Match. For his part, he'le be company for nothing but the Horſes; we won't have him with us.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I am heartily glad the Cur diſlikes my Company; ſince the profit I intend from him binds me from beating him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, where lives the Lady, and what's her name? If we can do you any ſervice, wee're both ready to wait on you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear <hi>Ned,</hi> that's kindly ſaid, and like thy ſelf; and you, <hi>Franck Friendly?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Moſt willingly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>It's old <hi>Pett</hi>'s Daughter, the <hi>Eaſt India</hi> Merchant; he lives at <hi>Hackney.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Say you ſo, Sir? I doubt I ſhall ſet you beſides the Saddle: This falls out as I could wiſh: This Fool making choice of me to keep him Company, brings me to kiſs the Hand of my fair Miſtreſs, and by that means to manage my affairs as I could wiſh.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, will you go, Gentlemen? I and my Man will walk before you, you may eaſily overtake us, for <hi>Moſes</hi> is as ſtiff as a Tree.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>We will not fail to follow you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Left. Moſes.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Lovewell,</hi> how lik'ſt thou this? The Fool comes on finely.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I have a deſign, <hi>Franck,</hi> in hand, will make us all men. You know he has made choice of us to be the means to make his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs love him. The ſame Lady that he ſpeaks of I have lov'd long; and ſhe has long lov'd me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear <hi>Ned,</hi> proceed.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>My fortune being ſpent before I thought on't, my Clothes
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:56777:13"/>decay'd, and having little left me to repair my ruines; all my pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings ſince have been by Proxy, excepting now and then a ſtoln vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſit over the Garden Wall; which lately in attempting, I was taken by her Father, and turn'd out by Grooms; which was the real cauſe of my late melancholy.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Td's death, then wee're undone; he'le know you again, and ſo we ſhall be us'd worſe than you were before.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Thy fooliſh fears, <hi>Friendly,</hi> have made us fail in many a fair deſign. Do you think the old fellow will know him again that he ſaw before but in half a Peruke, and not Clothes enough to cover him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>God-a-mercy, Blunderbuſs, he bolts out ſometimes to the purpoſe. I'le undertake, <hi>Franck,</hi> he knows me no more than I ſhould the <hi>Grand Seignior,</hi> if I ſaw him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>So the young Squire ſhall be at the charge of all Entertain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, till you have found a way to cheat him of his Miſtreſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Right; now let's follow him. But what ſhall we do with this Fellow? I'm certain, ſhould he undertake to walk it, he'le floun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der with his flat feet; and we cannot conveniently call for clean Lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for him in a ſtrange Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Pox on you for a couple of Puppys; I know you dare not carry me with you, for fear of diſobliging your Bubble. I'le meet you at Night at the Devil Tavern, for the Scene is alter'd ſince the Money came in; as long as that laſts I'le no more of the Can Office.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>A match; ſo God b'uy, blundering <hi>Tom.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Farewel, Fopps.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena tertia.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Juſtice Frump, Stingey <hi>his Clerk, and Goody</hi> Fells.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> you are a very fidling Woman, and are al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes worrying me and my Man for Warrants; what cauſe of Action have you againſt theſe men?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, an't like your Worſhip, I have 'em upon ſuſpitions of perjury. 'Tis well known to your Worſhip that I underſtand the Law; they both ſwore to me ſolemnly by the croſs of a Book, that they would pay me my Money on <hi>Monday</hi> Morning, and run away on <hi>Saturday</hi> Night.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:56777:14"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>That's right, the perjury lies good in that point. But how do you know they are gone?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I'le tell your Worſhip, without giving your Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip the trouble of many words, for your Worſhip knows I am not a Woman of many words: I wiſh I had more, for the good of the poor Pariſh I live in; if I had, I could get Money enough, by teach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of young Maids to talk at the Bake-houſe: for indeed, I help a great many Maids to Services, an't like your Worſhip, that ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times are able to give their Miſtreſſes but ſad accounts when they come home.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> fall to the buſineſs, and let me know how you are ſure your Lodgers have quite left you; for if they come again, the perjury is void in Law.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, then, I'le tell you, Sir; my Maid peep'd through the Key-hole, and ſee 'em put up all their goods in their pockets; and ſhe's without to juſtifie it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>It's a ſign they had a ſtrong Wardrobe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Why truly, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> that's a very good proof; <hi>Stingey,</hi> ſet that down in your Table-Book, that we may make a Preſident of it, for we have many of theſe Myſtical matters come be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore us; have you any thing more againſt theſe men? for I find the cauſe is foul o' their ſides.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Yes, an't like your Worſhip; they owe me ſeven ſhillings for Rent, beſides ſeven and ſix pence, for waſhing Linnen; and I hope the Law will allow me ſomewhat for the uſe of my own ſhift, I lent Mr. <hi>Faithful,</hi> whilſt his was waſht; for I can ſwear he wore it out extreamly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Goody <hi>Fells,</hi> in that caſe the Law ſomewhat differs. For <hi>Littleton</hi> ſays, what's lent is lent. But then there is a Statute of fifty ſixth of Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> that makes ſome proviſion in that caſe. <hi>Stingey,</hi> what is the Statute in that caſe?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, an't like your Worſhip, the Statute of Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> is a Statute in <hi>Statu quo;</hi> and you know, Sir, that the <hi>Engliſh</hi> of <hi>Statu quo</hi> is, <hi>what you lend, you loſe.</hi> Therefore I'm of Mr. <hi>Littleton</hi>'s mind, that <hi>what is lent, is lent.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> this is the very Letter of the Law; you muſt loſe the loan of your ſmock. I, but I'le make 'em ſmoak for the reſt. Have you made the Warrant, <hi>Stingey?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Yes, Sir, here 'tis.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>You muſt give me a ſhilling; Woman.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:56777:14"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>With all my heart, an't like your Worſhip; without of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence to your Worſhip, I think I know the price of a Warrant, as well as your Worſhips ſelf. I think they are all good, an't like your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>She ſumbles in her purſe, and pays him in farthings.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Stingey,</hi> direct her how to ſerve it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>He pulls out his Spectacles, and reades the farthings.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Carry it, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> to Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> the Conſtable; he is a whole-ſale Cobler, and my Maſters near Kinſman; he will be careful, for 'tis of great concern.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Bleſs your Worſhip; good buy to your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Goody <hi>Fells,</hi> pray do ſo much as change this farthing, I doubt it is not ſo right as it ſhould be.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Thomas,</hi> if you be remember'd, you left a penny Rowl un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paid of your laſt weeks breakfaſts.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Truly, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> I think I did; I'le pay it. Then, Sir, I muſt have but five pence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Fells.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>This will prove a crabbed caſe, <hi>Stingey;</hi> let's go in, and conſider on't: I proteſt, it almoſt confounds me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quarta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, Leticia, Fickle, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I wonder Mr. <hi>Leftwell</hi> comes not.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, here's one Mr. <hi>Leftwell</hi> deſires to ſee you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Deſire him to walk in. Daughter, remember your Duty, and receive him kindly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell, Lovewell, <hi>and</hi> Friendly.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, your Servant; I come to kiſs your Hand. Wan't that a-la-mode, <hi>Lovewell?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Very well; proceed, proceed.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I've made bold to bring my Friends.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> they're welcome for their own ſakes, and much more for yours. Gentlemen, you're welcome; pray be pleas'd to ſit down.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="22" facs="tcp:56777:15"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, which of theſe three is my Miſtreſs?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>This is my Daughter, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Sir, I like this little Gentlewoman as well
<stage>
                           <hi>To</hi> Betty.</stage> as her; but your Daughter has moſt Money, I believe; and 'tis that which makes the Mare to go, as the ſaying is.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>O this damn'd dogg! the Devil's in him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Well then, Lady; ſince you are ſhe, let me look upon you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I, pray good Sir, look, before you leap, by all means.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Can you find in your Conſcience to affect me? If you can't, let it alone, I'le look for ſome body elſe; for I ſuppoſe, there will be little love loſt. Let me ſee you look as if you were a little out of your wits. I hear you have a great deal of wit; I'le try you, look upon that Gentleman, he's able to ſay more in half an hour than you can anſwer in ſeven year, as wiſe as you are.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, has he more wit than you have, Sir?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I, a hundred times, and a hundred to that.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Then I aſſure you he's too hard for me, for I don't know what to ſay to you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I thought I ſhould put you to't But now I'le deſire <hi>Ned Lovewell</hi> to take you in hand; you ſhall ſee how much he can ſay more than I; I brought him to make love for me, but i'faith, I think I ſhall ſcarce find work for my ſelf. <hi>Ned,</hi> prethee lend me your place a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, and take you mine.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Sir; any thing to ſatisfie you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Pett,</hi> you muſt not be angry, for I am reſolv'd to have your Daughter, whoever I ſpeak to I'le but make a few pretty pretences to the reſt.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I proteſt, a pretty mettle'd man; I like his humour. I, I, Sir, make your ſelf as merry as you can.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Lady, how do you like me?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>So, ſo; you're a pretty kind of a man, but you wear your Clothes to the worſt advantage that e're I ſaw; your Bands are quite out of faſhion. Why don't you wear a Cravat? I fancy 'twould become you prettily, let me tye your Band like one.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Pough, let me alone, you'le all foul it. I hate this fooling: you think waſhing coſts nothing. I never ſaw ſuch a Woman in my life.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Then you ſhould wear a lace about your ſleeves; this makes you look ugly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="23" facs="tcp:56777:15"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I hope a man may look as he will, and wear what he will, for all you; it coſts you nothing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, 'tis nothing to me; but before I would wear ſuch ſhooe-ſtrings, I'de tye my ſhooes with blew tape.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, Coz, let the Gentleman alone; he wears what likes him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I'm glad you're come to my relief, I believe I ſhould have loſt all my Clothes elſe. I'le tell you this, Miſtreſs; had you been a Man, I'de a taken you over the face, for all your bravery.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>There's a Clown. I proteſt, Sir, I told him in kindneſs, never let me live elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>To</hi> Friendly.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me dye, Madam, if I don't think he deſerves to be hang'd. Was ever ſuch a dirty Raſcal? Ee'ne let him alone, Madam; I would not have you give your ſelf the trouble to laugh at him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> how do you like her? Pray, Sir, let me have her again. Give me your Hand, I'm a Horſe if I dont love you hearti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; now do you love me?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>How can I chooſe, Sir? every body muſt love you that looks on you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Then I'le take your Father aſide, and ſatisfie him how I love you, and what I intend to ſettle upon you; and ſo the work ſhall be done, before the World's aware of it. Mr. <hi>Pett,</hi> I deſire to ſpend half an hour with you in private.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>With all my heart, Sir; wee'le walk in, and return preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly. Gentlemen, you'le pardon us, bus'neſs muſt be done.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, we'le take a walk in the Gallery till you come again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Do ſo, Daughter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt ſeverally. Manet</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>This Fool, <hi>Leftwell,</hi> produces a brave opportunity to bring Mr. <hi>Lovewell</hi> and my Miſtreſs together; which there had been no way to have done without him; I hope, by this time, the affair is ſo well ſetled, that nothing can fruſtrate it. This Aſſe ſhall never carry her; if he does, both I, and all that are concern'd in the Plot, do undoubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edly deſerve a moſt infamous death.</p>
                     <q>
                        <l>In Love's affairs the Womens wits are beſt:</l>
                        <l>I'le Club my ſhare; let Fortune do the reſt.</l>
                     </q>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
                  <trailer>Finis Actus Secundi.</trailer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="act">
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:56777:16"/>
               <head>Actus Tertius.</head>
               <div n="1" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena prima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Clowt <hi>the Conſtable, Goody</hi> Fells, <hi>and</hi> Faithfull.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>A Way with him, away with him; you're my Pris'ner now: I'le have you up for my Rent, Sirrah, and my poor Maids money out of pocket.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Ha, ha, ha.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Bring him away, Captain <hi>Clowt;</hi> do you ſee how he laughs at you? Thus he ſerv'd me the very Night he run away with his Clothes. Come, Sir, I'le lend you a hand.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Conſtable, pray whither muſt I go; and what have you againſt me?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I have a Warrant againſt you for Felony, and Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>At whoſe ſuit, in the Devil's name?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>At this Womans; who is, Sir, as wiſe a Woman as any is in this Pariſh. You had beſt compound the buſineſs, and make the beſt of a bad matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>'Sdeath, I'le kick —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>How do you ſay, you'le kick me? kick me, Sir! I'de have you to know I am the Kings Conſtable, and cannot be kickt by any Chriſtian living.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le ſwear I heard him ſay he would kick ye; this ſhall come before Juſtice <hi>Frump,</hi> with the reſt; I warrant thee that it ſhall. You kick a Conſtable of the Kings, and a Captain of the Train'd Bands?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. Conſtable, give me leave to ſpeak a little.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>I tell you as I told you before, I am the Kings Conſtable; and 'tis not my place to give people leave to ſpeak that are my Pris'<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners. Therefore come on, Sir; I charge you in the Kings name, to come on.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I, I charge you in the Kings Name to come before Juſtice <hi>Frump.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:56777:16"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Goody <hi>Fells,</hi> what Commiſſion have you to command in the Kings name? Are you a Conſtable, Goody <hi>Fells?</hi> This is very fine, i'ſaith; I'le have that try'd as ſoon as e're we come before my Couſin <hi>Frump.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, Sir; you're a Captain, and a Conſtable; and a poor Woman muſt not have the liberty before you to be large in her own buſineſs, or elſe I could ſay ſomething. And 'tis not unknown to ſome of the Pariſh, that I underſtand the buſineſs of a Conſtable as well as the beſt <hi>Clowt</hi> in Chriſtendom.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>You underſtand the buſineſs of a Conſtable? Come, I'le put a queſtion to you. Provided, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> that you were upon the Watch, as I was laſt night.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Well; why, what then? Pray ſay on, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, and you take a Man upon the Watch. And you take a Man upon the Watch, as I ſaid before.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Under favour, Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> you have ſaid nothing elſe to the buſineſs yet.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Very good; The Man being thus taken, falls to play at Putt with one of the Watch-men upon the Watch; and falling to play, they fall out; falling out, they fall together by the ears. Preſently the Watch-man takes me up a brown Bill, and beats me out his brains. Now preſently after, there comes a Tryal between the Man kill'd, and him that kill'd him. Which has the Law o'their ſide? Now, Gam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer <hi>Fells.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>The Man that was kill'd fell out with him that kill'd him; ſo he that was kill'd, was kill'd <hi>Se defeddede;</hi> I know what I ſay, Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>Clowt.</hi> I ſay <hi>Se defeddede;</hi> which is to ſay, much againſt his will; therefore the Man kill'd has the right of the Law 'gainſt him that kill'd him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> you have done more, I proteſt, than Juſtice <hi>Frump</hi> himſelf could have done. If my Woman were dead, I would have thee before any Woman in the World.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Huggs her.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Land-lady, thou talk'ſt of wit enough for a Conſtable, thou art wiſe enough to make a Juſtice.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, Sir, there are ſome Conſtables have as much wit as ſome Juſtices. Pray, Sir, will you walk on, or I ſhall be fain to Command you in the Kings name again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> I want my Money; pray let's make what haſte we can.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>We ſhall drink one glaſs of Wine before we go.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:56777:17"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>To do you a kindneſs, Sir, wee'le drink one half pint: ſhall we, Gammer <hi>Fells?</hi> But remember, Sir, you threatned to kick me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt:</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena Secunda.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Leticia, Fickle, Friendly.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Now things are in this poſture, Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> pray have a care you put not all aſide by your neglect: my Father (I'm afraid) will make all haſte to expedite this Marriage. In having you, I venture all I have, or hope for; therefore have a little care extraordinary for her ſake that loves you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me not live under Heaven's light one minute after I for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get the leaſt of your Commands, from whom I've had ſuch honours heap'd upon me. Can you believe I can be ſuch a Slave, as to forget that thing is only able to compleat my happineſs?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I love to hear you ſay you love me, and 'tis becauſe I do be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve you do ſo. Yet I am ſad, and ſhall be, till I have eſcap'd the fears I live in, of being forc'd by my too rigorous Father to be fet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter'd to this fool of Men.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam, when they come back, then we ſhall find how far they have proceeded; by that we may know which way to order our affairs; of which I ſhall not fail by Letters to acquaint you con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtantly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>My Father will have ſuch an eye over me, that I'm afraid I ſhall ſcarce er'e be out of's ſight. He has been ſtrangely Jealous and Inquiſitive e're ſince he ſaw us in the Garden laſt (though now I think he knows you not again) therefore I doubt it will be very hard to have a Letter brought without his knowledge.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty</hi> and I have made a bargain will prevent all fear; my Man is to pretend Marriage to her; by which means, he may ſtill find admittance, and make her ſenſible, and ſhe you, of all my Actions, and deſigns: which will be weak indeed, if not able to out-do all that your old Father, and that Young Fool can e're contrive.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I like that well. Now, Couſin <hi>Fickle,</hi> how do you find the Gentleman? Is he well fitted? Have you look'd over his Linnen?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>How do you find your Friend, Couſin <hi>Let?</hi> Does he woe hard for Mr. <hi>Lovewell?</hi> I doubt he has been about his own buſineſs,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:56777:17"/>I ſhould like him the worſe elſe, and forget him (I mean the Fool) that threatned to beat me for adviſing him to wear lace about his ſleeves.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Shall I cut his tongue out for it, Madam?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>For Heaven's ſake do, Mr. <hi>Friendly;</hi> I'le love you as long as I live, if you will. I believe, Couſin, my Uncle and he will make the match againſt to morrow Morning, then thou art miſerable: faith, rather then ſo, let's riſe up before he comes. Thou ſhalt Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> and I'le ee'ne take Mr. <hi>Friendly</hi> here.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>A match, Couſin Mad-Cap; but I doubt you can't keep your word, nor live ſo long in one mind. I proteſt, if thou ſhould'ſt, I would ſweare thou wert never true to any thing, but Matrimony.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Madam, let me kiſs this hand for that kind contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, one ſhan't mock t'other; both, or none, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Both, a thouſand times together; but here they come.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, <hi>and</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I am ſorry we have made you ſtay thus long, Gentlemen; but Mr. <hi>Leftwell</hi> and I have done a good work ſince we went: we have ſet an end to wooing. Daughter, you're allow'd but two dayes to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pare for Marriage, and making of Wedding Clothes. I hope theſe Gentlemen will dance at the Wedding.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I faith, <hi>Ned,</hi> and <hi>Franck,</hi> the Lady there muſt Marry me, whether ſhe will or no. Why, you muſt, Miſtreſs, for all you look ſo. You two ſhall be my Bride-men, ſhan't they, Father <hi>Pett?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What you pleaſe for that, Son; the Gentlemen look like civil men, and will do very well.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, Dinner waits on your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, Gentlemen, will you walk in?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena tertia.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Faithful, Clowt, <hi>Goody</hi> Fells.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Was ever Man made thus Drunk by a Cuckoldly Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, and an Old Apple-Woman? Captain <hi>Clowt,</hi> the Kings Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:56777:18"/>lend me your Commanding Staff to lean upon. Let me ſee, you laid out all.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Not all; Gammer <hi>Fells</hi> paid eleven pence towards the laſt Reckoning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Captain <hi>Clowt,</hi> you're a drunken Dog, and I defie you, and there's an end o'th' Story; therefore ſtand further off. What place it this? where are we?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, this is the Worſhipful Juſtice <hi>Frump's</hi> Houſe; an Honourable Gentleman he is, I hope he'le hamper you, i'faith. If he don't ſet you in the Stocks for being drunk, and put you into Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon for my Money, he is not the Man I took him for.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>This Old Trot has not drunk her tongue out of rune yet. You Hell-Cat, with your Hoggs face, I'le ſo feague you with this faggot-ſtick.
<stage>
                           <hi>Enter</hi> Stingey.</stage> How now, who's this that looks as if he had been got between a ſtarv'd Quaker and a Holy Siſter, behind the door of a Conventicle? Come hither, Sir, let me ſee, is your Noſe made of Cheeſe?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Pulls him by the Noſe.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>O, O, O.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>O, ſay you ſo, Sir; I ſee, what e're your Noſe is made of, you have a tongue in your Head. What white-liver'd logger-head are you?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Frump.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>How now, Couſin <hi>Clowt?</hi> I ſee you are an honeſt man, and careful in your Office. Is this the Malefactor?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>An't like your Worſhip, Sir, this is the Man that made pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe of Marriage to the Maid, borrow'd her Money, cheated the Miſtreſs, wore out her own Shift, now does, or lately did wear out her Husbands Shirt, ſinfully ſwore to pay her her Rent one night, and ſhamefully run away, without any regard to his Oath, the next Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning. There lyes the perjury, an't like your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> give me leave to ſpeak in my own cauſe; I think I underſtand the Law a little better than a Man that has not been above a Moneth in his Office.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> you're a Fool in matters of Law; you know little of that: therefore I ſay, that I ought (being an Officer of State) to have the priviledge of ſpeaking, before any Woman that wears a Head.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Couſin <hi>Clowt,</hi> go on; let me have a full of the bus'neſs, that I may proceed to Sentence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Juſtice, I ſhall wring you by the red Noſe, if you liſten to
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:56777:18"/>that Logger-head any longer, before you hear me ſpeak. Therefore let's have a Bottle of Sack, and ſo conclude the buſineſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Bottles of Sack won't pay me my Rent, nor repair my Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen, nor take up the Perjury; and that's the point I inſiſt upon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, you pernicious old Whore you; wherein am I per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jur'd?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>How, de'e call Whore in the face of Juſtice? Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> bring your Action, I'le bear you out on't. Sir, I'le tell you the Law as to matter o'that. But hold, let us proceed to the firſt Indictment. <hi>Stingey,</hi> reade the Indictment.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Stingey <hi>Reades.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <p>
                     <hi>YOu ſtand here charg'd, by the name of</hi> Thomas Faithfull, <hi>at the Suit of</hi> Cicily Fells, <hi>of the Pariſh of St.</hi> Giles's <hi>in the Fields, in the County of</hi> Middleſex, <hi>Widdow; for Perjury, and breach of promiſe to the Maid of the ſaid</hi> Cicily, <hi>in point of Marriage, and the Sum of ſeven ſhillings, and ſix pence, with lawfull Intereſt and dammages for the forbearance thereof: for Lodging had at the Houſe of the ſaid</hi> Cicily; <hi>and moreover, in the ſum of ſeven ſhillings of like Money, for Laundry work done by the ſaid</hi> Cicily.</p>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, well; I'le pay it all. Little <hi>Ananias,</hi> you and I will go to a Wench.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, let me alone; I am none of thoſe you take me for: I go to a Wench? I'de rather dye than look upon a lewd Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, in the way of wickedneſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, guilty, or not guilty?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Honeſt old Raſcal, do one thing well in thy life, and lend your man Money to go with me, and have a leap; I'le ne're let go his Ear elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I proteſt, let go my Mans Ear, and plead, or I'le have you preſt.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, let go my Ear, or in earneſt I'le bring my Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>While they talk, Gammer</hi> Fells <hi>falls aſleep.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> awake, and hear the Judgment of the Court.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>She ſtarts up.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Tell not me of Judgment; let me have my Money, and the Man Married to my Maid, the King paid for the Perjury, and Mr. <hi>Clowt</hi> paid for his pains.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="30" facs="tcp:56777:19"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>His Worſhip muſt give Judgment, before the Malefactor can make payment, Gammer <hi>Fells.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Goody <hi>Fells,</hi> pray be patient; fair and ſoftly goes far, they ſay. Sir, you hear that your faults are of a high Nature; I'le tell you the letter of the Law in thoſe caſes you are now accus'd for. <hi>Plowden</hi> ſays, in his Pleas, and Reports, that, for Perjury, you ought to pay five ſhillings to the Juſtice you are brought before, and half a Crown to his Clerk. For Perjury is, <hi>Corpus cum eauſa,</hi> by the Statute of the Three and Thirtieth of King <hi>James.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Plowden's</hi> a Puppy, and you're an Owl; and I'le ſee you hang'd, and the Devil ride your ſtarv'd Clerk Hackney to Hell, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you ſhall have one penny of me. Juſtice, prethee, ſend for a Pint of Wine.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, ask any learned Lawyer about Town, they'le tell you, that <hi>Plowden</hi> was no Puppy; pray, Sir, pay but me and my Man the Money the Statute allows us, and I'le give you time for the payment of this poor Woman and her Maid.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Will you, faith, Juſtice <hi>Frump?</hi> That is fine, Juſtice <hi>Frump:</hi> ſhall I be fobb'd off now with a promiſe of payment? Did I put my Cauſe into your hands for help, and you to put the perjury Money into your own pocket? are you willing, forſooth, that I muſt lye by the loſs? Is this Juſtice? No, 'tis Jewiſhly done.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>To him, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> to him, to him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> let me have my Money, and I'le take a courſe for yours. Pray, Sir, will you ſatisfie me and my Man, and pay for the Perjury?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Will your Worſhip be pleas'd to hear me?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>If you have any thing to ſay for your felf, why Sentence ſhould not paſs upon you, pray ſpeak, and remember the payment of the perjury Money. If I han't it, 'tis ſo much Money out of mine, and my Man's pocket, I proteſt to you; and that's all the Woman ſtands upon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>It's falſe; and your Worſhip is little better than a Lyar in ſaying ſo: 'tis my own Money I want.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Woman, Woman, let your betters be ſerv'd before you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Juſtice, you promis'd to hear me ſpeak; pray be as good as your Word.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>You have liberty to ſay any thing, ſo it be to the purpoſe; and pray remember the perjury Money. Woman, you ſhall have ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="31" facs="tcp:56777:19"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Then, let but Chitterlin-Chops, your Man, here, go but with me to a Bawdy-Houſe, and I'le ſend you your Money due upon the perjury; my Land-lady ſhall have ſatisfaction, and I'le Marry he Maid. I'le play your Puppy but one hit.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Take your Cloak, <hi>Stingey,</hi> and go along with the Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man; 'tis a caſe of neceſſity, and no ſin; for we ſhall loſe ſeven ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, and ſix pence, elſe; conſider, <hi>Stingey,</hi> ſeven, and ſix pence, is Money.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Now, I'le ſee you all burn'd firſt, and ſo take your Courſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Stingey,</hi> make his <hi>Mittimus;</hi> and away with him, Couſin <hi>Clowt.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>I made the <hi>Mittimus</hi> before, an't like your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Stingey,</hi> make him pay for't, and bring me in my part. Couſin <hi>Clowt,</hi> take care of him; for I'me reſolv'd to hamper him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Frump.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Come along, Sir; once more I charge you in the Kings name.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, pay me for making the <hi>Mittimus.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Codds head, come hither — Be a good Husband, and keep this till I come again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Gives him a box on the Ear.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>O Lord, how ſhall I anſwer this to my Maſter?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Bring him along; I'le never leave you, till I ſee him ſafe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quarta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, Leftwell, Lovewell, Friendly, Leticia, Fickle, Betty, <hi>in a Garden.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, I wiſh your Cheer had been better; but expect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing none but my Son <hi>Leftwell,</hi> I have provided leſs than I ſhould have done, had I had warning of your good Company.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, your Entertainment has been like your ſelf, moſt truly generous and Noble.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I vow, Father, I have ſpent a ſhilling many a time for a din<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, between <hi>Moſes</hi> and I, and have not dyn'd half ſo well.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>This is a very pleaſant Garden, Sir; and that row of Trees adds much to the beauty of the Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I believe 'twould be very pretty, if the Plot were alter'd,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:56777:20"/>and the Trees taken down at the end, and a gravell Walk made.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>If the Trees were remov'd to day at thy Requeſt, Niece, to morrow thou would'ſt wonder why they were taken down, and be for tranſplanting them again ſome where elſe. I'm confident thou would'ſt not like them half an hour in any place; therefore, prethee leave thy prating.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I perceive by your humming (Mr. <hi>Lovewell</hi>) you Sing well, therefore let me engage you to give us a Song, whilſt we ſit down in yonder Arbour. Nay, I will not be deny'd; and my Couſin here, in requital, ſhall give you another.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>If you love me, honeſt <hi>Ned,</hi> do my Miſtreſs that kindneſs. Come, don't be out of Countenance, Man. Why, there's no harm in ſinging in Civil Company; is there, Father <hi>Pett?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>No, truly, Son, I think not.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, to ſerve you and your Lady that muſt be, I would ſing till I had loſt my Lungs; but I am ſo unfitting now. Madam, your Ladyſhip muſt undergo the whole brunt of the buſineſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, <hi>Ned,</hi> when wee're alone, that word ſhall be ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing in thy way, I'le aſſure thee, take my word for't; he has a Cold, and can't ſing. Pray ſing you, forſooth.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Yes, pray oblige us.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, we believe your excuſe juſt, and another time ſhall ſerve.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Honeſt <hi>Ned,</hi> let me tell thee, thou ſing'ſt as well as any Man in the World, when thou art well; would I were a Woman, for thy ſake. Thou art a ſweet Rogue. Have a kindneſs for him, dear Miſtreſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Ladies, I fear if I had ſung, I ſhould have made your Heads ake, for all Mr. <hi>Leftwell</hi>'s Commendations; but let me beg the perfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mance of your promiſe, Madam.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, let's have the Song you ſung to us laſt night; I like it very well. Come, no excuſes, but do it.</p>
                     <stage>
                        <hi>To</hi> Fick.</stage>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Since, Madam, there's no way to avoyd it, I'le obey your Commands. But I hope, Gentlemen, you'le not be angry with me for making a noiſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Pretty Miſtreſs, make an end of the Prologue, and come to the matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Song.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>What ſay you, Gentlemen, how do you approve of my Kinſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>womans Voice?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>As I hope to live, Madam, your Voice would invite me from my Prayers to liſten to it, were I ſure not to live above half an hour after.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="33" facs="tcp:56777:20"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>P'ſhaw, waw, wherein is her Voice ſo good, as to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwade you into an Opinion on't; I have heard a Hogg, when a Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiff Dog has hung at his Ear, make better Muſick: I wiſh her Song were in her guts, ſo we had one of <hi>Ned Lovewell's.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> you do her wrong, to ſay ſhe Sings not well; beſides, it calls your Judgment in queſtion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I think I ſhould have as much Judgment in Singing, as ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Man, for my Father taught me for two years together; there is not an old Song that ever was made, but I can ſing it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> will you oblige me, and the reſt of the Company, with any one you can conveniently ſpare, now we are in the Singing humour.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>For thy ſake, my Sweet heart that is, and my Wife that muſt be, I will ſing, ſay, or do any thing.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, Sing then; ſhe deſires you that you would.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O good Sir, let's hear your Song.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Not for your ſake, Miſtreſs; for you're to be my Maid with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in theſe two dayes; and ſhall I do any thing at the requeſt of my own Servant? No, I ſcorn it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>But Madam <hi>Leticia,</hi> your Miſtreſs, and I, your Friend, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire it; pray, Sir, let's live no longer in Expectation.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Leftwell <hi>Sings.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <lg>
                     <l>
                        <hi>WHen as King</hi> Henry <hi>Rul'd this Land,</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>The Second of that Name;</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>Beſides the Queen, He dearly lov'd</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>A Fair, and Princely Dame.</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>Moſt Peerleſs was her,</hi> &amp;c.</l>
                  </lg>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>No more of your Ballad; I proteſt my brains are ready to ſplit: I had rather be ty'd to a load of Iron, and be drawn after it quite through <hi>London,</hi> than hear your Servant ſing ſuch another Sonner.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>You're a fooliſh Gitle; this was one of the prettyeſt Songs in <hi>London,</hi> when I came to Prentice firſt. You don't know what a Song is; Sing on, Son.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="34" facs="tcp:56777:21"/>
                  <stage>Leftwell <hi>Sings.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <lg>
                     <l>
                        <hi>Her Favour, and Her Face:</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>A Sweeter Creature in the World</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>
                        <hi>Did never Prince Embrace.</hi>
                     </l>
                  </lg>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>'Tis true, the Song is good, Sir; but Mr. <hi>Leftwell's</hi> Voice is at preſent, a little out of Tune; and ſo if he pleaſes, wee'le have the reſt another time.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Indeed, I have got a kind of a Cold; but when ever (if thou haſt a mind to hear it) 'tis all at thy Service. When we two are abed together, I'le lull thee aſleep every Night, and wake thee every Morning with my Voice, becauſe I ſee thou delight'ſt in it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Without doubt, as much as I do to hear a little Boy beat upon a <hi>Bartholomew</hi> Drum.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>A ſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Father, I muſt be forc'd to take my leave of you; I have a Houſe to Let, in <hi>Long-Acre,</hi> that calls me away (as a Man may ſay) <hi>Nolens, Volens,</hi> from you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, pray, Sir, ſtay, and take a ſmall Supper here too; you and your Friends ſhall be as welcome as I know how to make you; ye ſhall have a good Bed, and clean Sheets; ſo much I dare promiſe you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, if you promis'd a thouſand things, I muſt go when I have buſineſs to do, and there's an end of it; and ſo, your Servant, Sir. Good b'uy, my Dear; prethee don't take on, I'le be here again to morrow morning. 'Tis to no purpoſe to grieve, you'le get nothing by that but your labour for your pains, in a manner. Let me intreat you to take this parting partiently.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I'le aſſure you I'le keep my heart as whole as I can till I ſee you again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, your Servant; wee'le wait on you to the Door. Sir, I hope you and your Friend will do my Son the kindneſs, to un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dergo the Office of Bride-men.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I ſhall be proud to have the honour of ſuch Services.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I do equally eſteem my happineſs with his; and will not fail to pay my due attendance.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Sir; may you live long, and happy.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="35" facs="tcp:56777:21"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Did you ſee my Man <hi>Moſes,</hi> Mrs. <hi>Betty?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Yes; he, and old <hi>Ralph,</hi> were drunk an hour before Dinner; and are gone to ſleep.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, when the Rogue wakes, bid him rowl home after me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt omnes, praeter</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Now will I prepare my old Maſter to Licenſe my Young Lover to the freedom of Viſiting me; by which the whole deſign can't chooſe but take effect.</p>
                     <lg>
                        <l>Aſſiſt us, <hi>Cupid,</hi> for thou know'ſt 'tis fit</l>
                        <l>Beauty, and Youth, ſhould be rewards of wit.</l>
                     </lg>
                  </sp>
                  <trailer>Finis Actus Tertii.</trailer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="act">
               <head>Actus Quartus.</head>
               <div n="1" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena prima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>FRanck,</hi> the Fool comes on as I could wiſh; h'as ſent me a Letter, wherein, he ſwears he loves me moſt monſtrouſly: ſome way we muſt find out to get more money from him, the better to enable us to cheat him of his Miſtreſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>My little Mad-Cap ſwears ſhe'le have me at the ſame time when you have yours. And if her kindneſs but continue, I ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve my ſelf a happy Man; for as I live, I love her infinitely. But prethee let's ſee <hi>Leftwell's</hi> Letter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>He'le be here preſently, he ſends me word; but ſince you love to reade a well-penn'd Letter, this is it, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Friendly <hi>Reades.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <p>
                           <hi>AFter my hearty Commendations, my love remembred unto you,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>I deſire that you would prepare your ſelf; and get</hi> Franck <hi>to do the ſame</hi> (viz.) <hi>to be my Bride-men; for my Miſtreſs vows ſhe will not have me, unleſs I can get you to be as good as your word. I would not have you fail me, for five hundred pounds; for if you do, I ſhall loſe a Wife worth ten Thouſand. And ſo I reſt</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Your Dutiful Friend, <hi>Leftwell.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <pb n="36" facs="tcp:56777:22"/>
                  <p>Here's an Epiſtle, with a pox; did ever man ſee ſuch a Puppy?</p>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>But now, ſuppoſe we ſhould pretend our Chambers were robb'd when we went with him to <hi>Hackney,</hi> of the Money that ſhould have furniſht us with Clothes, and neceſſaries, to have attended at his Wedding. What ſay'ſt? Wilt do well?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>By this light, nothing like it; is he to meet you here?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>So the Meſſenger ſaid.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le immediately put my ſelf into a melancholy poſture; but I'm afraid thou'lt never counterfeit well.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>O! feat not that. Hold, here comes the Cuckco — let's ſeem not to ſee him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell, Moſes.</stage>
                  <stage>They pretend not to ſee him; but walk diſcontentedly over the Stage.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Why <hi>Ned!</hi> why <hi>Franck!</hi> why <hi>Franck!</hi> why <hi>Ned!</hi> You ſee I'm not worſe than my word. I'm juſt for <hi>Hackney</hi> now, the Wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding Clothes are gone before; once more, I beg you not to fail me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Sir, would willingly perform what Service my ability can reach to; and ſo, I'm certain, would <hi>Franck</hi> here; but —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>But what? why, what's the matter, Man? Why, thou art grievous Melancholy. Prethee, tell me what's the matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Alas, Sir, 'twill but trouble you to hear your Friend's miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortunes.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>For my part, Sir, I grieve not at my own, I could laugh at them; but that I ſhould fail you, it makes me almoſt mad.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, dear <hi>Ned,</hi> tell me what's the matter; I proteſt, you make tears ſtand in my eyes: let me know the cauſe quickly, or I ſhall cry out-right. I would not, I proteſt, for a thouſand pounds, you ſhould fail me; I ſhall loſe ſuch a fortune, I ſhall never have again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>That's the greateſt of my grief; that you, my Friend, from whom I have found ſuch favours, ſhould be ſo great a loſer in my ill luck. 'Sdeath, I could kill my ſelf.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>O, for the love of God, good Gentlemen, as you love me, and as you love your Miſtreſſes, let me know what troubles you; I proteſt, I'le tear my Periwigg to pieces elſe. <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> will you tell me or no? or I will tear.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Friend, put on your Periwigg; to ſee you in this paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, adds to my ſorrow; and ſhould I tell you now, I know your good nature would lead you to repair our loſſes, which I hate the very thought of, knowing how far we are already engag'd to your Libera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="37" facs="tcp:56777:22"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>The Coxcomb, I find, will be wrought upon. Dear diſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mulation, how I love thee!</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Never ſpeak of that, man; if Money will make up the mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, ne're be melancholy; I have juſt now receiv'd two hundred Guineys for the Fines of four Houſes.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>But with what confidence can I do this? Pray, Sir, pardon me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>By this hand, either let me know what 'tis that troubles ye, and take my Money to make up the matter, or I'le ne're come near you more, though I know I ſhall loſe my Miſtreſs by it. I thought you had had more kindneſs for me, than to hinder me thus of a Fortune; now you have woo'd her for me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, Sir; ſince nothing will ſatisfie you, the caſe is thus. That day we went with you to <hi>Hackney,</hi> our Lodgings were broke ope, and robb'd of all our lac'd Linnen, and almoſt two hundred pounds beſides; ſo that we ſhall want Money, and all things elſe, to furniſh us to do you Service in that garb we willingly would, had not this ſtrange misfortune hinder'd our Intentions.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>P'ſhaw, and is this all? Look, here's all the Money I have about me: I'le ſend <hi>Moſes</hi> home for more.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Alas, dear Sir, half this will ſerve; pray pardon me: but ſince you'le have it ſo.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Why ſhould it not be ſo? I ſay, it ſhall be ſo. Go home, <hi>Moſes,</hi> fetch the Purſe that lyes behind the Cabinet. I'le away to <hi>Hackney;</hi> you'le come on Thurſday, before nine a Clock.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, wee'le be there before you are up, I warrant you. I do aſſure you I know not what to ſay, that may in the leaſt make ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction for ſo great a favour.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I am equally unhappy in the want of words, to expreſs my gratitude.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Pugh, I can't Complement; you have got it, and much good may it do you; and ſo farewell.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear <hi>Ned,</hi> let me ſpit in thy Mouth for thy Ingenuity; faith, 'twas very well done.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>As I live, it went againſt my Conſcience all the while I was about it; and I ſtrangly wonder I went ſo well through with it, to wheadle a Man out of his Money, and cheat him of his Miſtreſs too; 'tis enough to damn an honeſt Man to do it, and make a wiſe Man mad to undergo it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>'Twere honeſt in no caſe but this; for this is but eaſing of
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:56777:23"/>a Brute with half a Soul, of a few of his Fathers ſins; and beſides, if we get theſe Fortunes, we may pay him his Money again. Then, for his Miſtreſs (if ſhe were his, as ſhe's yours) you do a deed of Charity, to preſerve her from being bound to a Fool; beſides—</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Enough, enough, <hi>Franck;</hi> theſe Reaſons are ſufficient to reſettle my ſtruggling Conſcience.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>But now, what's to be done, as to the Ladies? they live in expectation of relief from us; and I long to know a way to ſend it them.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I've made <hi>Runwell</hi> our Agent here; and we ſhall have by him the Courſe we are to ſteer. The Ladies will give full directions by him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Enter a Meſſenger.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Friend, lyes your bus'neſs with any here?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Meſs.</speaker>
                     <p>I have a Letter for one Mr. <hi>Lovewell.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I am the Man; whence comes it?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Meſs.</speaker>
                     <p>The Letter, Sir, will give you ſatisfaction.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit Meſ.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>'Tis <hi>Faithful's</hi> Character, I think.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Lovewell <hi>Reads.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>Dear <hi>Ned,</hi>
                           </salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>
                           <hi>WHen this Letter finds you, come to my Relief as ſoon as you can; for I am cram'd into a little Room in</hi> New Priſon, <hi>where I am like to be over-run with Lice, and ſtifled with ſtinking Tobacco. Tell</hi> Franck Friendly, <hi>that I was taken upon a Warrant, at the Suit of our Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lady</hi> Fells, <hi>for Rent; and committed by one Juſtice</hi> Frump: <hi>but the Keeper ſayes, hee'le let me out upon any Bail; provided, I pay my Fees. So fail not, dear Friend, with all ſpeed, to reſcue</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Your Servant, <hi>Thomas Faithfull.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>O that damn'd Juſtice! he once committed me, for piſſing under his Window.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, <hi>Franck,</hi> leave prating; and let's haſte, to help the poor Rogue.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Was there ever ſuch a Toothleſs Trot, as this? who the Devil put it into her mind? But let's ſtay no longer.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="scene">
                  <pb n="39" facs="tcp:56777:23"/>
                  <head>Scena ſecunda.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leticia, Fickle, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Couſin <hi>Fickle,</hi> there is nothing in the World makes me ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mire more, than to ſee thee ſo long in one mind; that thou ſhould'ſt love one Man two dayes together, is little leſs than a Miracle.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>And nothing but a Miracle can make me miſs him, as we have laid the Plot. If they come according to our appointment, wee'le be Married two hours before my Uncle, and the intended Bride-groom, are awake; but ſhould I miſs him to Morrow, I'de have him the next place I meet him in. My Uncle cannot hinder me, though he may you; nor ſhall, from marrying any Man that I affect.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>O Coz, that I were but in thy Condition; and as free from the fear of a Father! but I Vow, my heart begins to fail me; if we play this trick to Morrow, when he miſſes us, hee'le certainly run ſtark mad; and turn me off, without a penny Portion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Girle, fear not that; he may be angry for a Moneth, or ſo, but no longer; for he has never another Child. Nature will engage him to come about again, and give thee all; hee'le be as kind as ever, never fear it. However, wilt thou weigh thy Fathers anger, in compariſon, with the loſs of gentile Mr. <hi>Lovewell?</hi> Let me dye, if I am not aſhm'd to ſee thee have ſuch idle fears.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>The Scene is ſtrangely alter'd; when thou com'ſt to counſel any body to Love and Conſtancy; but Coz, doſt think thou canſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue this humour, till to Morrow?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Leave your tatling; for I queſtion your reſolution more than you need mine; I could find in my heart not to let you go to Bed to Night, leſt you ſhould lye too long in the Morning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, I will never be out-done by thee, in point of promiſe; I will be up, and ready to meet him; go, and be immediately Marri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to him, though I turn Seamſtreſs for my Living. Therefore come along, Girle.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Said like thy ſelf, ſweet Coz; if it be done to Morrow, wee'le laugh one Day, let what will follow.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Have you fully inſtructed <hi>Betty,</hi> that ſhe may ſatisfie Mr. <hi>Lovewell</hi>'s Man, the time and place they are to meet us in? You
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:56777:24"/>know I left all that to your care: has ſhe the Letter for him?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>To th' full, fear not: let's in, and put our Jewels up; for if the Old Man proves unkind, they may ſtand thy Friends; I'm ſure he muſt pay me my Portion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Ex. ambo.</stage>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Runwell,</hi> I have got ſuch a bundle of bus'neſs here will make you mad to carry it, and your Maſter mad with joy to hear it. Tell him, and Mr. <hi>Friendly,</hi> that the Ladies deſire their Companys by four a Clock to morrow Morning, at the corner of our back-gate, with a Coach. But here's two Letters, which if you give your Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, will ſave you the trouble of telling a long Story. So pray be careful, and farewell.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> Mrs. <hi>Betty;</hi> unleſs you pity me, my Maſter has utterly undone me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, what's the matter, man?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>Here he has ſet me to wooe in jeſt, and I'm in love in earneſt. Unleſs you think you can love me, I am bound to wiſh I had never ſeen you; for I find in my ſelf I cannot live without you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O, if that be all, leave it to me; and as I find your care in your Maſters concerns, ſo you ſhall find my love towards you, if you are in earneſt. Fare you well, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>This is ſhort, and ſweet; it ſavours ſomething of kindneſs: but what I ſhould do with a Wife if I had one, I can no more tell, than a Taylor knows how to make a Horſe-ſhooe. And yet I love this little Rogue ſo well, that I muſt have her, though Ruine were ſure to follow: however I hope my Maſter, when he has got his Miſtreſs, will help us out at a dead lift. But I muſt make haſte.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="scene">
                  <pb n="41" facs="tcp:56777:24"/>
                  <head>Scena tertia.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, Ralph, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Ho! where are you <hi>Ralph?</hi> is the Cook come?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Ralph.</speaker>
                     <p>Yes, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Bid him come to me; <hi>Betty,</hi> do you get Mrs. <hi>Snuff,</hi> the Houſe-Keeper, to make the Wedding Bed, ſhe knows what be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs to ſuch matters; and look that the Hangings in the Matted Room be bruſht down, and the Chare-Woman rub the reſt of the Rooms. Let every thing be done in Order.</p>
                     <stage>Enter Cook.</stage>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. <hi>Lard,</hi> look that every thing you undertake be done de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cently; ſpare for no coſt, but call for every thing you want. I would not be niggardly at the Wedding of my only Child. Has Mr. <hi>Plume,</hi> the Poulterer, ſent the Cram'd Capons, the tame Pidgeons, and the Partridges. And, <hi>Betty,</hi> ſtep to the Butler, and ſee whether he has Bottel'd the two Tearces of Claret, and the half Pipe of Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary. Pray look about you, and let every thing be done that may adorn the Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Cook.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, let me have but Meat enough, and things convenient to carry on the work of the day, if I don't lick my fingers after the <hi>French</hi> Mode, and make ſawce as well as any Man of my Profeſſion, let me be put into Pye-Cruſt, and ſent a Sacrifice to the unappeas'd Stomacks of unſatiate Serving-men.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I'le ſee that every thing be ready to your ſatisfaction, as far as I'm concern'd, and look that the Bride be dreſt before Eight of the Clock, or the Cook ſhall cut me into Steaks and Stew me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>God-a-mercy, good Girle; get thee about thy buſineſs then, for thou haſt a great deal to do.</p>
                     <stage>
                        <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Lard,</hi> queſtion not but you ſhall have every thing, to furniſh out a Feaſt for the Entertainment of a King. Command what's neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary for the Kitchin.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Cook.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me alone, then; I'le warrant your Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exit.</stage>
                  <pb n="42" facs="tcp:56777:25"/>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Morrow, Father; pray, how does your Head?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Very well, Son; pray, why do you ask?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Only to be ſatisfy'd, Sir, becauſe mine akes, and turns round, as if 'twere about to look for another ſeat, and would take leave of my ſhoulders; why, there is not a pair of hands in the Houſe but what's in motion, to make as much noiſe as they can; all the great Guns in a Sea-fight ſing treble, in compariſon of the Thundring baſe that Reigns in every Room here. Pray, Sir, what's your deſign in this? Do you intend to make me mad before I'm Married?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Sir; but I have a deſign to have my Houſe ſet in Order, and to make proviſion for thoſe that ſhall entertain you and your Bride to Morrow; and do you think this can be done without noiſes? I warrant you would have had the Victuals ſent to the next door to be dreſt, and ſo brought through the Street to the Table. Pray, Son, if the noiſe be ſo troubleſome to you, let you and I go to the back-ſide of the Houſe, and play a game at Tables; are you for Iriſh, or Back<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gammon?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Sir, I have ſworn never to throw a Dye more, though I have plaid at Dublits, and loſing Lodum, before now; but I have quite left off Gaming. I care not, if I go up ſtairs, and ſee my Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs; A Man goes in danger of his life here below: I, by chance, look'd but into the Kitchin, and one of the Cooks took me for a Calf, I believe; and in ſpight of my teeth would needs ſpit me. Then my ſhins have been broke three times to day, by ſtragling Stools that ſtept out of the places they ſtood in this ſeven years, and lay now where I never look'd for 'em. I had like to have had my face waſht too, by the Fellow that cleans the Wainſcoat; his Cloath was within an ace of my Noſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, Son, there is no help for theſe things; but ſince you have made choice of your Miſtreſs for your Protectreſs, you may find her, and my Niece <hi>Fickle,</hi> together at the Chamber at the end of the long Gallery.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt ſeverally.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="scene">
                  <pb n="43" facs="tcp:56777:25"/>
                  <head>Scena quarta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly, Faithfull, Squeeze <hi>the Gaoler, as in a Priſon.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>How now, <hi>Tom,</hi> Revelling?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>O, are you come? By your favour, fellow Pris'ners, I muſt ſpoil the Dance.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Garry this Crown to the poor Pris'ners; farewell, Friend. Are you fully ſatisfy'd?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Squeez.</speaker>
                     <p>He is diſcharg'd, and may go when he pleaſes.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Lord, <hi>Ned,</hi> how this Fellow looks! Let me ſee, what does he look like?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, faith, he looks like a poor Whore, turn'd out of an Inns of Court, half drunk, at four a Clock in the Morning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Or like a Gipſie, that has been let down a Chimney, and drawn up again with a Gammon of Bacon at her Breech.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, Gentlemen, had you been where I was, it would have made you look a little uglier than ordinary.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>If thou wert but a little uglier than ordinary, as thou ſay'ſt, a man might endure to look on thee, <hi>Tom;</hi> but, as I live, thy Face looks juſt of the colour of a Red-herring, and thy hands like a Saylers, that have been ſteept two dayes in Tarr and Tallow. And any body will ſwear, by thy Linnen, thou haſt robb'd a <hi>French</hi> Lacquey.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>This Fellow ſtinks ſo of Tobacco, that there is no way to make him ſmell ſweet, and look like a man, but to take him down to the <hi>Thames,</hi> and have him drawn twice, or thrice, croſs the Water at the tail of a Sculler.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Say you ſo, Signior Snowt? if you bee'nt ſmoak-dry'd in the ſame place before you have waſht your Hands for to morrow's Dinner, I'le be bound to hang for you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, was there ever ſuch a ſimple ſot as thou art? To have money in thy pocket, and be ſent to Priſon for fourteen ſhillings: Why the Devil did you not pay it? but it may be you had a mind to ſee the Lodging you muſt laſt live in.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>If you had given her the money, ſhe had no more to do with you; one would imagine you want brains as well as money; but
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:56777:26"/>perhaps you've a fancy to be lowſie: But wee'le let that paſs. Look, here's more money, <hi>Tom.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>What, from the ſame hand, Ladds?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>This is nothing; there is that in hand will make us all hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py:</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>If that which is in hand won't, I don't know what will: come, what deſigns have you, let me know all?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, wee'le truſt you for once; we two are to be mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried to morrow to two of the greateſt Beauties and Fortunes within twenty miles.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Where, and to whom, dear Rogues, tantalize me no lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, <hi>Tom,</hi> I don't know yet my ſelf; but here comes one, I believe, will better inform me; what news, <hi>Runwell?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I muſt have leave to take breath, before I can tell my tale; you muſt be by four a Clock to morrow morning, and Mr. <hi>Friendly</hi> with you, at the Corner — But here's a Letter will fully inform you; and here's one for you, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>By this hand, <hi>Franck,</hi> I'm afraid to look into mine, leſt there ſhould be leſs in it than I expected.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I'm under the ſame ſence of fear; prethee, <hi>Ned,</hi> open thine, and put me out of pain.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>'Tis better to know a man's Fate, than fear it: I'le venture.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Reades.</stage>
                  <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <opener>
                           <salute>SIR,</salute>
                        </opener>
                        <p>
                           <hi>BE ſure you fail not to meet me, and Mr.</hi> Friendly <hi>my Couſin</hi> Fickle, <hi>at the Corner of our Garden in the green Meadow, about four of the Clock to Morrow Morning: Provide your Parſon ready at ſome Church in</hi> London, <hi>that may do the bus'neſs, without delay. My Conſin is as well re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd for Mr.</hi> Friendly, <hi>as I am for you.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Your Servant, <hi>L. P.</hi>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                        <postscript>
                           <head>Poſtſcript.</head>
                           <p>
                              <hi>Pray ſend back your Man, that he may be with</hi> Betty; <hi>ſo if the bus'neſs ſhould fail, he may be able to help us.</hi>
                           </p>
                        </postscript>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
                  <pb n="45" facs="tcp:56777:26"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Mine is, <hi>Franck,</hi> as I could wiſh; how ſounds thine?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>There's all the harmony of love in't; but <hi>Ned,</hi> what ſhall we do for a <hi>Levite?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Leave that to me; I'le provide Old <hi>Legit,</hi> the Reader, who is in Orders, and will do the bus'neſs as faſt as a Biſhop, and tye you together to Eternity. And I can borrow the Keyes of the Sex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton of St. <hi>Giles's</hi> for leſs than five ſhillings, and a full Flaggon of mild Beer. Therefore bear up, Boys.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>You're ſure you can do this; if you fail us, wee're all un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>done.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Conſider, <hi>Tom,</hi> our bus'neſs is your own; for as the caſe ſtands with us, ſo it does with you; either happy, or miſerable.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Trouble your ſelf no further; if I fail, one of you ſhall have my Ears, and t'other my eyes. So farewel, Friends; I'le about it inſtantly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Faithfull.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Run you back to <hi>Betty,</hi> and ſtay there till you hear from me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>I flye, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Franck,</hi> go you and provide the Coach, and I'le make every thing elſe ready: meet me to night at the Devil Tavern, there wee'le ſtay till two a Clock, and ſo ſet forward.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le not fail.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="5" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quinta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell, Leticia, Fickle, Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I ſhould take it very kindly, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> if you would go now, and give me leave to go to bed.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Bride will never get up to morrow morning to be mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried, if you keep her up ſo late to night. Pray, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> leave us.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I won't go till I pleaſe: may'nt I do what I will, if I have a mind to't, with my own Wife? I believe my Father would give me leave to lye with her to night, if I askt it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>What, before you are married? That would be a ſight worth ſeeing indeed. I'faith, if you won't go down, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> I ſhall make bold to beat you down with the Bed-ſtaffs: What, I'm ſure my Old Maſter did not ſend you up to day at Noon, to ſee us a bed. Will you be gone, and give my Miſtreſs leave to go to Bed? I ſhall beat you down with the Bed-ſtaff elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:56777:27"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Hold<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> don't beat him, wee'le perſwade him civilly. Pray, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> be Civil, and do not undertake to ſtay longer, where it cannot be allow'd of with modeſty.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Lord, Sir, is your Stomack ſo great, that you can't ſtay till to morrow Night, and ſo take lawful Poſſeſſion? but preſs in in an ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gall manner into a place a day before you have a priviledge. I aſſure you, the World will think you want wit ſtrangely in attempting it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, if I don't go down, and do your Etrand to my Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, Miſtreſs, let me live lowſie, and dye upon a Dung-hill. For your part, I ſhall turn you out of Service to Morrow
<stage>
                           <hi>To</hi> Betty.</stage> night, like a ſawcy Slut as you are. And I'le beat your ſweet-heart, till his bones rattle in his skin: I ſwear by my Sword, I'le ſqueeze him like a Turnip between two Trenchers; and there's a word for all.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Now hee's gone, let's not trouble our ſelves to talk of him, but make proviſion for the Morning's Adventure. 'Tis now almoſt twelve, and you know they'le be at the back-gate by four a Clock in the Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning; and ſhould we ſpend that time idly, 'tis ten to one, but it may bring us to repentance, by unkindly failing our Gallants. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore let's fall to packing up thoſe little things we have, to help us in neceſſity; then ſleep an hour or two.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I proteſt, I'le not go to Bed for all the World; if I do, I ſhall certainly loſe my Lover, I alwayes wake ſo late a mornings. But if <hi>Betty</hi> will ſit up, and promiſe to wake us, wee'le lye down in our Night-Gowns till that time.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>With all my heart, Madam; I'm an errant Slut, if I would not, to promote this buſineſs, ſit ſix dayes, and as many nights, up to the Chin in Water, this cold Weather. For I have ſuch a Faith in both the Gentlemen, that I am very confident they'le make you hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> thou ſhalt not fail to ſhare in my good fortune; and now go to your own Chamber, and be ſure to call us in time. You know what you have to do; ſtay behind with <hi>Runwell,</hi> and be the firſt that miſſes me; and do it with all the paſſion imaginable; ſo you'le be unſuſpected.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam, I had rather puniſh my ſelf in being abſent from you (ſince 'tis your command) than be wanting in any Service I may poſſibly do you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>That's my good Girle; but let me kiſs thee firſt for good lucks ſake.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="47" facs="tcp:56777:27"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Good night, good Ladies.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Now, Couſin, we're alone, what's to be done?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Let's ſleep two hours, and riſe before the Sun.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
                  <trailer>Finis Actus quarti.</trailer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="act">
               <head>Actus Quintus.</head>
               <div n="1" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena prima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, <hi>and</hi> Friendly.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>COachman, ſtay you there, ſtir not till we come back. 'Tis devilliſh dark, <hi>Ned;</hi> not ſo much as a Star ſtir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>And cruel cold, <hi>Franck;</hi> if my love wan't very hot, 'twould ne're hold out the battery of this bitter Morning. If the poor Ladies are abroad, I'm ſorry for them, I fear it bites them ſeverely. Prethee where art? canſt thou not keep cloſe?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I am by you here; but know not in what place.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, I thought I ſmelt you; but come nearer, I'le be a little unkind to my Noſe, and keep you Company at preſent, for want of a ſweeter. But hold, I think, wee're near the place appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted: prethee, come up; is not that the Garden Wall?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>You may as well perſwade a blind man to do you the kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, to draw your Picture, as to ask my opinion now; for I can no more ſee thy hand, than I can my own face; nor canſt thou ſee any thing, unleſs thou haſt chang'd eyes with a Cat. But heark, I hear ſome body, and ſee a light yonder.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter the other way,</hi> Leticia, Fickle, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Cupid</hi> be kind to you, and lend you a lanthorn, 'tis cruel dark: good Ladies, keep your Gowns cloſe about you, for I fear youl'le catch cold.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Couſin, I'm afraid to ſtir; would they were come,
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:56777:28"/>I have got the Cramp in every one of my fingers, with cold; if I ſtay here but half an hour, I ſhall be fitter for burying than Marriage: I'm afraid I ſhall loſe the finger the Parſon is to put the Ring on. Pray <hi>Betty,</hi> which finger is that?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Madam, I don't know.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Nor I; if I did, I would be ſure to keep that from the cold. Couſin <hi>Let.</hi> thou look'ſt ſo pitifully, for want of thy Morning's Poſſet, that, o'my Conſcience, I could cry for thee. Give me thy hand, where is it, Girle? Take comfort, I warrant they come.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I dare ſwear 'tis they; let's go a little nearer.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Art ſure there's never a Ditch in the way? Would we had the Women, and were well in the Coach again: But give me thy hand, and I'le go with thee.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I vow, Couſin, my courage was almoſt cold; but to ſee thee ſo confident in thy ſufferings, or indeed, to do thee Juſtice, ſo conſtant; I now believe it a meer ſhame to come ſhort of thee. Whatever hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens, I'm reſolv'd to ſtay here till they come, not to be unfix'd in my Reſolutions.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Poor Miſtreſs, I ſhould queſtion the Juſtice of the gods, ſhould they forget to be your Friends, and fail to help you; nay, I ſhould think they had forgot to further goodneſs, if they ſhould let you be a loſer, in proſecution of ſo pure a love.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Never fear, <hi>Betty,</hi> wee'le through now, though froward Fate had ſworn to ſet a ſtop to it. But heark, I hear the ſteps of ſome body: would I knew who they were; it ſtartles me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Coz, now thou art faint-hearted again; 'tis nothing but the leaves of the Trees that hang over the Garden Wall. Let's walk a little further forwards.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>There's a Candle, <hi>Lovewell;</hi> let's look a little nearer: ſtay, is not that <hi>Leticia?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>And I am monſtrouſly miſtaken, if that ben't thy Miſtreſs, and <hi>Betty</hi> that holds the light; look, they come nearer.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I think I heard ſome body ſay, <hi>Leticia:</hi> and I begin to loſe my fear, and will look a little further. <hi>Betty,</hi> light hither a little.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>The Candle goes out.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O Lord, Madam, the Candle's out, I'm undone. I ſhall never find the way back to the Gate upon the Cawſey.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>They come up to them in the dark.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam, <hi>Leticia,</hi> Lady; here's no body anſwers. <hi>Franck,</hi> art ſure 'twas they?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="49" facs="tcp:56777:28"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>No, it may be we ſaw Angels in their ſhapes; 'twas either the one, or the other, I can aſſure you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>No, my dear <hi>Lovewell;</hi> 'tis too late to keep at diſtance, when there lacks ſo little time to make us one; here's ſhe that loves thee; and if Heaven were pleas'd to lend us light, would joy to look on thee.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sweeteſt <hi>Leticia,</hi> why art thou ſhrowded in this ſheet of darkneſs, that ought to fear, and flye from ſuch a Face, though it pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumes on all the earth beſides? Speak but once more, that I may find thee by thy Voice; ſince my eyes are unſerviceable.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned, Ned,</hi> have you found your Miſtreſs? If you have, lend me your hand to find mine; for I dare as well be hang'd, as ſtir a foot further than the place I'm in: I'm juſt now up to the belly in the Horſe-pond.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Hold, Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> let me call her: Coz, Coz.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Lord, where are you? I hear Mr. <hi>Friendly</hi> make ſad com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints, but I proteſt I don't know where to find him. Are you here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts, Couſin?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>I, where is your hand?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Here, and here's <hi>Betty</hi>'s; I am glad I have found you: Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> your Servant; if you would ſpeak, I ſhould be glad to hear you, for I proteſt, I cannot ſee you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam, your moſt humble Servant; I would <hi>Franck Friendly</hi> were as near you as I am: poor Rogue, he lyes poring up and down in the dark for you; <hi>Franck, Franck.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Here, here, at hand; is my dear Miſtreſs near there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abouts?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>She's here, with Madam <hi>Let.</hi> and <hi>Betty.</hi> Thou art the only loſt Sheep of the Company; here, have a care, thou wilt blunder over ſome body; prethee, be careful, take me by the hand.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I ſhould be happy if I had it; hold, is not this it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>What do you think?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, I don't know very well; but I'le feel for the <hi>Roman</hi> T. that will ſatisfie me the truth on't.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>One would have thought the ſpirit of Jokeing had been drencht out of you in the Horſe-pond; but here's the hand of your fair Miſtreſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I, here's a hand indeed, makes me forget all wet and cold, and fear of future Storms.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>But if you ſtay much longer here in your wet Breeches,
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:56777:29"/>you'le remember wet and cold again, in ſpight of your Antidote; and I'm ſo wet with dew, that unleſs you make haſte, I ſhall dye before I'm Married; and ſo be put upon ugly work in the other World; you have heard the Proverb: and beſides, you will loſe my Portion, which is no poor one.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, dear Coz, let's ſtand no longer in the cold tatling of Eſtates, but haſte to the Coach; have you brought one?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I, and four Horſes, that will hurry us to <hi>London;</hi> and a <hi>Levite</hi> that will do the buſineſs: we ſhall be there by five a Clock.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I, but we ſhall not get into the Church ſo ſoon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>The Sexton has provided a Bottle of Wine, and ſome other things, for your diverſion, till ſeven a Clock, at which time you will be miſt here, and the work will be doing there.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Let's away to the Coach then. <hi>Betty,</hi> 'tis ſomething lighter now, you may eaſily find the way back; and be ſure you remember your inſtructions, you know where to ſend to me; ſo fare thee well, good Girle.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty,</speaker>
                     <p>I vow, Madam, I muſt weep at parting, though you are going about to do that buſineſs I have alwayes wiſhed you; but aſſure your Ladyſhips, I'le ſerve you both to the utmoſt of my power; and ſo the god of Love preſerve and proſper your proceedings.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Friend.</hi> Pretty Mrs. <hi>Betty,</hi> your Servants.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Ex. omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="2" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena ſecunda.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter Gammer</hi> Fells, Clowt, <hi>and</hi> Mold <hi>the Sexton.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I charge you, Neighbour <hi>Mold,</hi> make a Confeſſion before Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> the Kings Conſtable, of what you told me laſt Night, as you and I ſat in the Chimney Corner at my Houſe, drinking a dram or two of Brandy; by the ſame token, you took the Bottle out of my hand, whilſt I did ſomething; but that's no matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Neighbour <hi>Mold,</hi> diſcharge the part of a good Chriſtian, and clear your Conſcience, by making your Confeſſion to a Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble of the Kings; who is a Member of State. Indeed you may object, though I am one of the Kings Conſtables, you are one of his Sextons too; true, it is ſo; and that is in part ſatisfaction: for it is unnatural
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:56777:29"/>for one Member to perſecute another: ſo, if the buſineſs were only 'twixt you and I, 'twere eaſily made up. But here's my Neighbour <hi>Fells,</hi> truly, a Woman that underſtands the World, has been wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly dealt with, has a great deal of Money due to her, and much linnen worn out; has lain long in wait for one of the Men, that ſhe ſayes, nay, ſhe ſwears, Neighbour <hi>Mold,</hi> you told her was to come to your Houſe this Morning, from thence to go to Church to be Married. Therefore I command you in the Kings Name to ſpeak the truth.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Or elſe I'le have a Petition, to have you before Juſtice <hi>Frump.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>How, a Petition, Gammer <hi>Fells?</hi> you have forgot all your Law, as if you had never had any. A <hi>Suppina,</hi> Woman, a <hi>Suppina;</hi> that's the only way. A Petition? I cannot forbear laughing; I tell you, you cannot do it any other way, but by a <hi>Suppina.</hi> Ha, Gam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer <hi>Fells,</hi> you have not ſo good a Head-piece as you had formerly. Well, well; Age, Age.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly, Leticia, <hi>and</hi> Fickle.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Now, my dear Miſtreſs, we are ſafe from all our fears; this is the Sexton's Houſe, there wee'le repoſe a little, then to Church.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Are you come, i'faith, Sir; Seize on him, Mr. Conſtable, in the Kings Name; this is the other Rogue, that ow'd me Money, and forſwore himſelf. Come, bring them all away: for, Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> if one body in a Company be perjur'd, all the reſt are guilty, and muſt ſtand in the Pillory with him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> 'tis very true, you're in the right in that caſe; ſo I command you all, in the Kings Name, to come away with me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Miſtreſs, if any body here owes you any thing, I'le pay you preſently five times as much, if that will be any ſatisfaction; pray, put us to no trouble, for wee're about earneſt buſineſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>You ſay honeſtly, Sir; pray be as good as your word, and let me have but thirty ſhillings, and I'le diſcharge you; for I love a Gentleman, as I do my life.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Here's your Money; ſo fare you well.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Hold, Sir, hold; how ſhall I be diſcharg'd by the King for the perjury? You muſt go fore Juſtice <hi>Frump,</hi> and ſtand the Tryal.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="52" facs="tcp:56777:30"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, who in the Company is perjur'd? Pray, Mr. Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable, ben't ſo impertinent, but let us go about our buſineſs.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, that is that Gentleman; and you being in his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, are, with all the reſt, equally concern'd. So I command you come away, in the Kings Name.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>That's true indeed, the perjury is not diſcharg'd; bring them away, there's no remedy; I would it were in my power to do you any good: Come, Neighbour <hi>Clowt,</hi> bring 'em along; I'm afraid you'le lye by't.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le not go along with you, not ſhall any of the Company. This Old Bawd has couzen'd me of ſome Money, and I believe you intend to cheat me of more.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>Offer to draw, I'le knock down your Wench here; will you come on quietly, in the Kings Name?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Conſtable, here's five pounds, let us but paſs now; and wee'le promiſe to meet you to Morrow Morning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I wiſh he would, i'faith; if he takes it, I ſhall tell Juſtice <hi>Frump,</hi> and ſee how he'le take it; perhaps he'le cheat the King too. Come, come, Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> the Law lyes not in your Hands; if I live, I'le ſee 'em laid up; and if you don't look to your Office, look to your ſelf; ſhall People be perjur'd, and go unpuniſhed?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, good Woman, what are you concern'd? your debt is ſatisfy'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Is it ſo, Goody Gillyflurt, with your face full of patches? you ſhall know that I am not ſatisfy'd; 'tis ſuch as you make poor Men they can't pay their Debts: where have they pickt up you and that Puppet, your Companion? I'le have you where you ſhall give an account of your ſelves, and what buſineſs you have with theſe Men.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>You abominable old Bawd, I'le kick you, till you curſe your own Blaſpheming tongue.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>How? Do you kick an Antient Houſe-Keeper before the face of me the Kings Conſtable? Sir, I would have you to know, you have forfeited your foot by the Laws of the Land, therefore look to't. Neighbour <hi>Mold,</hi> I command you in the Kings Name to aſſiſt me; have a good heart, Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> I'le ſee you ſatisfied. Come on, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned,</hi> wee're utterly undone if we go before the Juſtice, for hee'le be ſure to commit us, right, or wrong, if it be but to get his Man Money for the <hi>Mittimus;</hi> of which he himſelf has the largeſt ſhate.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="53" facs="tcp:56777:30"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I don't know what to do. Mr. Conſtable, will nothing ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie you, unleſs we go before the Juſtice; you would do us a fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour, if you would take our words till to Morrow; and heark you, Sir, here's five pounds to buy your Wife a Ring.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>I proteſt, Sir, I would do it, though you had kill'd my Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, for ſo much Money; but Gammer <hi>Fells</hi> will have a fling at my Plumb-Tree, and utterly undo me, therefore I cannot do it: Pray, Sir, come along.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. Conſtable, will you allow the Ladies liberty to go to a Friends Houſe, whilſt we go to the Juſtice's.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>The Ladies, with a Murrain; no, Sir, they ſhall go with you, and ſee how they like lying in a Gaol. Captain <hi>Clowt,</hi> come along, I'le lead the way, therefore look to the Pris'ners.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, there's no remedy; Ladies, don't be dejected though; Juſtice muſt diſcharge us.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I do'nt care if the deed be done before my Uncle hears of it. You may go; Mr. Conſtable, wee'le follow you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt, The Scene alters.</stage>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter again, at</hi> Frump's <hi>Houſe.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Conſtable, if you deſign our March much further, pray let's have a Coach, for the Ladies are not us'd to foot it ſo far.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Clowt.</speaker>
                     <p>This is the Houſe, Sir; pray be patient, I'le have you no further.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Stingey.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Morrow, Mr. <hi>Clowt;</hi> I ſuppoſe, by the people you have brought with you, your buſineſs is to my Maſter; I'le ſtep in, and call him; Mr. <hi>Clowt,</hi> in the mean time, pray be careful of the Pris'ners.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>What peaking Puppy's this, that looks as if he quarter'd with a Camelion, and eat nothing but Air?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>By this light, he looks like one that was got by a Beggar, and has liv'd ever ſince lowſie. But who's this that looks ſo like a Knight Templar, with his Chopps muffled?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="54" facs="tcp:56777:31"/>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Frump.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Stingey,</hi> the Speech I have been getting by heart theſe ten dayes will now do me a kindneſs to this Company; therefore do you hold the Paper, whilſt I ſpeak; if I chance to be out, you may put me in with a whiſper, and pretend buſineſs; for it is excellent good, and well penn'd by a Counſel learn'd in the Law; and now I'le begin. Hum, ha. Gentlemen, I know not what you are, nor from whence you come; you may be this, or you may be that. But for this or that, it is no matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>How, an't like your Worſhip, no matter? your Worſhip ſhall know that the matter is conſiderable, both to the King, and to your ſelf, for all theſe People are perjur'd; and you know by that there's many a penny coming in. And they came from <hi>Hackney,</hi> and theſe Wenches belong to Mr. <hi>Pett,</hi> of the ſame Town; and I have ſent him word of it, and he'le be here preſently, I preſume, under fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour of your good Worſhip.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Woman, hold your prating, or I proteſt, I'le ſet you into the Stocks; would her tongue were out, ſhe has put me quite beſides my Speech; where abouts was I, <hi>Stingey?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, you were at, But for this, or that, it is no matter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Then, Gentlemen, But for this, or that, it is no matter; as I was ſaying before. You know the time of a Juſtice of Peace is precious, an Antient Author ſayes, concerning the life and living of Juſtices; who ſayes, their labour is much, and their care great: therefore I command you, Gentlemen, and Gentlewomen, that you do not weary me with long Circumſtances, to unſettle my head, but I pray be ſatisfy'd, and ſubmit to Juſtice; for your offences are of a fearful — What's next, <hi>Stingey?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Conſequence.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Of a fearful Conſequence; and indeed, moſt crying Crimes, as the learned <hi>Felton</hi> ſayes, <hi>Libera nos Domine.</hi> But let him ſay what he will, he was a Juſtice; I am one, and have in this Houſe the Kings Commiſſion that made me ſo.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>I believe your Worſhip's a little miſtaken; ſure, Sir, Mr. <hi>Felton</hi> was a Parſon, and not a Juſtice.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Come, come, let me tell you, there is no difference be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween 'em, learn that from me. You're a Young Man, &amp; have not ſeen ſo
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:56777:31"/>much of the World as ſome have. But, as I was ſaying before, I am a Juſtice, and have the Kings Commiſſion for it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, <hi>and</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Juſtice <hi>Frump,</hi> your Servant; I'm glad to ſee you, Sir, and have made haſte to do it. Gentlemen, you have done kindly by me, I'm beholding to you; ſo is my Son <hi>Leftwell</hi> here. For your parts, Gentlewomen, you ſhall along with me again. Good Woman, come and Dine with me on <hi>Sunday,</hi> I'le give you ſatisfaction for your care. Hereafter I ſhall watch you both a little better.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>You are an honeſt Gentleman, Sir, and I'le be ſure to come according to my promiſe; I'm glad that it came into my heart to hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der theſe ſweet pretty Gentlewomens marriage with theſe beggarly Fellows.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Beggarly enough a Conſcience, good Woman; they were not ſo well clad as <hi>Adam</hi> in Paradice, before I lent 'em Money to make 'em Clothes; no, not ſo much as Figg-leaves, Gammer <hi>Fells:</hi> and theſe wretched Raſcals, to reward me, come betimes in the Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, and run away with my Miſtreſs, juſt when I ſhould have mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried her; no Devils would have done ſo.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>O wicked Knaves; I warrant you, Sir, Juſtice <hi>Frump</hi> will give them their Reward for it; to go to cheat ſuch a pretty, ſweet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fac'd, likely, hopefull, young Gentleman as you are.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Juſtice, your Servant. Daughter, and Neice, you have deceiv'd me once; but if ever you put ſuch a trick upon me again, I'le forgive you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. <hi>Pett,</hi> I ſhould be glad, if the Law would give me leave, to let your Relations go; but they are equally concern'd with theſe Gentlemen, and muſt go with them to <hi>New Priſon:</hi> 'tis pity, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe they are pretty Maids; but Juſtice muſt not be ſtifl'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> wee'le give you ten ſhillings, if you'le ſay you miſtook the Man; and that this is not he: you will get nothing by keeping of us, nor will Mr. <hi>Pett</hi> know how to get off his Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and Couſin; ſo you'le loſe your reward there too.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>I'faith I'le do't, for I love a Gentleman as I do my life.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I'le be bound to ſave you harmleſs; and I'le ſtay at my <hi>London</hi> Houſe this Moneth, where you may ſend for me at any time: and here's ten ſhillings for your Clerk.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="56" facs="tcp:56777:32"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>There is five for me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fells.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, your Worſhip, I proteſt, I miſtook the Man, this is none of him, I thought it was; and unleſs you ſet them all free, I'm undone; they'le ſue me, they ſay, till I have not a groat left to help my ſelf: Good, your Worſhip, conſider a poor Woman.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Gammer <hi>Fells,</hi> if you ſay ſo, I muſt diſcharge them; pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided, they gratifie my Clerk, which is a thing common.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Sir, moſt willingly; there's ten ſhillings for him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, Mr. Juſtice, if they are diſcharg'd, I hope theſe are ſo too. Fare you well. Gentlemen, pray let me ſee you no more near my Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>By my Sword, if I ſee you near the Houſe again, I'le kick you both upon the place I firſt meet you, though it be a thouſand Miles off. So good b'uy, honeſt Friends, good b'uy.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt omnes, praeter</hi> Love. Friend.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>That this blund'ring Fellow ſhould tell the Sexton our names, and the names of the Ladies, and the place from whence they came.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>There was no other way in the World, to bring all out, and utterly ruine us; we are utterly undone, <hi>Ned;</hi> and I do believe 'tis impoſſible ever to bring it about again. Here comes the Cox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comb.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Faithfull.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>What a pox is your meaning? Alwayes playing the Fool thus, to ſend me to get a Parſon, and provide every thing, and then never come: Indeed 'tis like you; I kept my <hi>Levite</hi> in the Church from four a Clock in the Morning, till 'twas nine, that he ſwore he was almoſt ſtarv'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>You have done us good Service; if you had your reward, your ears ought to be cut, for the mighty care you took in our con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns; Indeed, you ſhould have ſatisfaction.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Indeed, <hi>Thomas,</hi> you have undergone a great deal, and done more by half then we could have deſir'd you. If the Devil him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf had given you directions, you could not poſſibly have made us ſo miſerable.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray tell us ſeriouſly, what have we done to you, that ſhould provoke you to ruine us in this damnable manner? Is it your
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:56777:32"/>cuſtom, pray, to betray your Friends in the drinking two Pots of Ale? Lord, Sir, how you look about you, as if you had loſt your way in a Wilderneſs. I'le warrant you don't know what you have done, now.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Not he, I'le warrant, 'twas done in his ſleep; does he not uſe to walk, <hi>Franck;</hi> you have lain with him? By this light, I take him to be ſo honeſty that he would not do ſuch a thing waking. Wer't not aſleep, <hi>Tom,</hi> when thou told'ſt all?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, you have been very free, both in your Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations, and your Accuſations, and yet I have ſaid nothing; pray will you give me leave to ſpeak.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>I; pray, what would you ſay?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I ſay, I'le be hang'd if this be any thing but a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign to ſtop my mouth, and keep me from quarrelling with you, about the abuſe you put upon me, to make me ſtay in the Church ſtarving in the cold with a great greaſie Parſon.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>No, no, <hi>Thomas,</hi> you are monſtrouſly miſtaken; for if that were all, you know we're well enough able to deal with you; we can ſoon knock you down with words. But pray let me ask you one thing: How many Pots of mild Beer did you and Mr. <hi>Mold</hi> drink before you came to the matter; I mean, before you made the diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of my Name, and <hi>Franck Friendly's,</hi> and both the Ladies, and from whence they came?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>And pray let's know why you did it, and what you got by doing of it; and whether the Devil be yet out of you, that was in you when you went about it; pray be pleas'd to ſpeak: what, are you tongue-ty'd? Don't gape, but ſpeak, Man.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, and what hurt did this do you?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>It has only ruin'd us, that's all. But why the Devil ſhould you make a confident of an old ſottiſh Fellow, that is not ſatisfy'd with cheating the living, but dead too; ſure you might have done your buſineſs without giving him a particular of our Names.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Gentlemen, how has this undone you, let me but know the meaning on't?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, the Sexton over-joy'd with the Money you had gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven him, and happy that he had news to carry to his Neighbours, went ſtrait to Mother <hi>Fells</hi> (living hard by) and being drunk with her, told her I was one of the Perſons concern'd; ſhe ſtrait gets a Warrant, and ſtayes at the Sextons, takes him and me, and both the Ladies; ſends home word to old <hi>Pett,</hi> who, whilſt we were at your Juſtices,
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:56777:33"/>fetches them both away. Now, you have heard your Crime to the full, pray what have you (with a pox) to ſay for your ſelf?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, <hi>Tom,</hi> I don't know what ſatisfaction you can give us; unleſs you will conſent that we ſhould cut your throat.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I, for Heaven's ſake do it quickly; I acknowledge I deſerve it, pray diſpatch, I hate to live one minute after I have been ſo great a Brute, to betray my Friend by folly; I was curs'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee Coxcomb, leave raving, and let's ſee what may be done to bring all about again; for being ſure of the Ladies, our caſe is not yet deſperate, they are now at their <hi>London</hi> Houſe; the Scene lyes ſomething nearer then it did.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>To make you ſome part of ſatisfaction, I'le go and kill <hi>Leftwell.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Now he talks of killing <hi>Leftwell,</hi> I've a deſign in my head, may hap to do us good.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, what is it?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, <hi>Faithfull</hi> ſhall ſend <hi>Leftwell</hi> a Challenge, and in it, unleſs he meet, threaten to Piſtol him, and write to me to be his Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond; and then — heark — what doſt think of this, boy?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>They Whiſper.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, <hi>Ned,</hi> I think — Pray, Sir, be quiet, we'le not have a thought of yours in the buſineſs. <hi>Ned,</hi> this would do rare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, if we could find a way to let the Ladies know on't; how muſt that be done?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I'le tell you how.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, good muddy brains, if thou would'ſt hold thy prating, and ſay, nor do any more than you have directions from us, things may be carried on well enough.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>If a Man commits but one fault in his life, he ſhall be ſure to hear o'nt; pray, proceed then, and let it be purely your own, and be pox'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>How ſhall they know our intentions?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I expect <hi>Runwell</hi> every minute, who will not fail to do it dextrouſly.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="59" facs="tcp:56777:33"/>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>See where he comes.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>The poor Ladies, Sir, are utterly undone if you can find no way to relieve them; Madam <hi>Leticia</hi> is to morrow Morning to be Married to this Looby <hi>Leftwell.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Runwell,</hi> come in with me, I'le ſend a Letter to her of one de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign more, which I hope will take; <hi>Thomas,</hi> pray provide us one Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon more preſently.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le warrant you; if I don't, let me dye for't.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>But have a care of Carouſing again with the Sexton. <hi>Ned,</hi> you and I'le go write the Challenge, and the Letter; for the Pinci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pal has forgot to reade; but however, I'm ſure he can't write.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>My laſt fault makes me at preſent a little lyable to the laſh of your ugly tongue; but I'le let you alone till the buſineſs is done, and then have at you.</p>
                     <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                     <p>So god b'uy, I'le go find out my Doctor.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Both.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray do.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes, ſeverally.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="3" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena tertia.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leticia, Fickle, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Was ever ſuch an unhappy Accident as we have met withall, to ruine our intention: If there be a god of Love, he has very little kindneſs for us; dear Couſin, what ſhall we do?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>pretend thy ſelf ſick, and ſo avoid it; I proteſt, were it my caſe (as it is thine) I would rather dye, than have <hi>Leftwell,</hi> he looks ſo like a Horſe-courſer. For my part, I'm reſolv'd to have Mr. <hi>Friendly</hi> at one time or other, though he ow'd all the Ale-wives in Town Money.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Thou talk'ſt, Couſin. But prethee (if thou canſt) tell me a ſerious way.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Why then, I'le tell you; when the Parſon asks, whether you'le have him, ſay no; then I'm ſure nothing can be done: what think'ſt thou of that, <hi>Betty?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="60" facs="tcp:56777:34"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I vow, Madam, I think you direct very well. Pray, Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, take her advice.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>Madam, my Maſter ſends his Service, and this Letter; from Mr. <hi>Friendly</hi> this to your Ladyſhip.</p>
                     <stage>
                        <hi>To</hi> Fickle.</stage>
                     <p>Dear Miſtreſs, pity a poor Lover, that lives yet only in hopes that you will make him happy. Pray look upon me; faith, I ſhall be loſt elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>To</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Good Lover, let your Maſter be ſerv'd before you. Pray, Madam, what ſayes Mr. <hi>Lovewell?</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> I hope that this device of theirs will make us happy. <hi>Runwell,</hi> go back, and tell them wee'le obſerve their directions.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Runwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>For my part, if I fail in any thing, let me — Here's my Uncle, and the Wiſe-Acre.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, <hi>and</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What Paper was that you put into your pocket?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Only my Taylors Bill for my laſt Gown, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, Love, let me look on't; for by that I ſhall know what you'le ſtand me in.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, forbear; when you come to pay for what I wear, you ſhall have leave to look; till then, you have no Authority, nor ſhall have over me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le fetch you down in your Wedding ſhooes, i'faith, for this; to Morrow night you ſhall give me twenty kiſſes to come to Bed to you, or the Devil take me if I do it; and you are a ſawcy —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Son, Son, you're too paſſionate; let her have her humour, for once, and keep her Paper.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="61" facs="tcp:56777:34"/>
                  <stage>Enter to them, a Servant.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, here's a Letter was left juſt now for Mr. <hi>Leftwell.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Let me ſee it.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>He reades.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>This is the Challenge; ſee how his colour turns, Couſin.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Indeed, he looks pale.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Oh, I'm undone, I'm undone: I would your Daughter had been drown'd ten times her depth, before I ſaw her; I'm undone, I'le have none of her; I'le not be kill'd for any Woman in <hi>England,</hi> not I; look here, do but look here; this is from one of the gang of thoſe Rogues that ran away with her this Morning: I don't like her ſo well, as to loſe my life for her; and theſe curſed Rogues will never leave till they have kill'd me; undone, undone.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Pett <hi>reades the Challe ge.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> take comfort, don't ſnob ſo, and be ſatisfy'd; you are ſafe enough in the Houſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Mrs. <hi>Fickle,</hi> but I an't ſafe in the Houſe; the Rogue may bring a Cannon, that may carry quite through the Houſe for ought I know, and kill me, ſo as no body ſhall know where to find a piece of me afterwards, to tell who hurt me; would I were a thouſand Miles off. O good Ladies, ſpeak a good word for me, let me have ſome comfort from you quickly, I ſhall faint elſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I Proteſt, 'tis a bloody deſign. Daughter, I'le reade it to you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>O dear, Sir, if you reade, I'm a dead Man; I can't endure to hear my own Sentence; pray, put it into your Pocket, for I proteſt to you with tears, and upon my knees, that I am ready to ſwound at the ſight of it. Sweet Sir, let me ſee it no more, if you deſire I ſhould live.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee Son be ſatisfy'd, I warrant I'le keep thee ſafe in the Houſe from any harm; nothing ſhall hurt you here.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I tremble as I ſtand, I proteſt, for fear I ſhould be blown up; I'le be hang'd, if he has not put Gun-powder into the Cellar.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Do you think ſo; indeed, Mr, <hi>Leftwell,</hi> it will pleaſe me mightily, to dye in ſo good Company as you are; for if the Houſe be blown up, we ſhall all go together.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I don't know how it may pleaſe you, but I proteſt, I can't endure to think on't; I had rather ſee you, and a hundred more ſuch, blown up together, than be a party concern'd. O that ever I ſet my
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:56777:35"/>eyes on that Woman: now muſt I dye for going about to do you a Courteſie.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Truly, Sir, I'm ſorry you're like to ſuffer thus for me; I had rather, I aſſure you, not have you, than you ſhould be injur'd:</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>You are a couple of diſſembling Sluts; I'le warrant you'de be glad to ſee me hang'd, to have me afterwards.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, there is one Mr. <hi>Lovewell</hi> at door, very earneſt to ſpeak with you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>O, then I'm a dead Man, hee's come to kill me. Pray good Ladies, pity a poor Man, and ſtand before me; if I ſcape killing this time, I'le never go about to Marry more.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I am aſham'd to ſee you ſuch a Coward; a Man, and cry? I'le ſend for him in, and know his bus'neſs; if I find him concern'd, I'le have him ſecur'd. Pray, Son, ſatisfie your ſelf.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Secure him! that will do me a mighty kindneſs indeed, his being ſecur'd after he has kill'd me. Before he comes in, let your Servants feel in his pockets for pocket Piſtols, and Daggers, and ſeize upon his Sword.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>That's not much amiſs, it ſhall be ſo: Go tell him, if he will ſuffer that, he may come in; elſe he may ee'ne walk back again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I wonder what he ſhould come for; I don't care for the ſight of him, ſince he ſeduc'd me laſt away, and brought me into your diſpleaſure.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>We ſhall ſee preſently.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, <hi>and Servant.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Your Servant, Sir; I have ſuffer'd a very ſevere ſearch; be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I could obtain admittance. I muſt confeſs you have ſome reaſon to think ill of me; but now, Sir, I am ſenſible how much I had like to have injur'd you, and that deſerving Gentleman.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Points at</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Oh, he points at me; Mercy, Mercy: dear Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> let me but live one Three or Fourſcore years longer, and then you ſhall find me very willing to lay down my life at your Service. O, let
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:56777:35"/>me not be cut off in my prime, before I have receiv'd half a years Rent of my Eſtate.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, what doſt thou mean? pray be pacify'd; he has no deſign againſt you I dare ſwear.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear Father, ſtand before me though; for ſay what you will, I'm afraid to truſt him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> if you have any buſineſs, proceed.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I thought my ſelf, in point of Honour, bound to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover this bloody deſign laid to deſtroy your intended Son-in-Law. Look upon this Letter, Sir.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Pett <hi>Reades.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>I proteſt, Sir, I think my ſelf much engag'd to you, if we could by your means apprehend him. My Son-in-Law has already re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd the Challenge; and it ſeems, he has choſe you for his Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, that's the thing I came about; if you will get a War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant for him preſently, you'le find both him and me together, at the Sign of the Lamb, within two doors of Juſtice <hi>Frump</hi>'s; I'le go be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, and get him ready.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Now, truly, Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> we both eſteem our ſelves much beholden to you, and will endeavour to make you amends.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>All I deſire, is, pardon for my laſt error. Your Servant, Sir; Ladies, your Servant.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Lovewell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I'm glad he's gone; for he has frighted me out of the ſmall ſence I had.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Son, will you go along with me to apprehend him?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Sir; I thank you for that, I'faith; I'le as ſoon thruſt my Head into a hot Oven, as venture my Noſe an Inch without the Door, for one of theſe Doggs to ſnap at.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Well, then; I'le take my Servants, and do it without you.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Pett, Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>My Father's gone; I wiſh they were here now.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>What ſhall we do with this Fool <hi>Leftwell?</hi> he'le run after my Maſter, and fetch him back again, when he ſees us going: look where he comes ſneaking, like a Prentice
<stage>
                           <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell.</stage> that has loſt his Maſters Money at play.
<stage>Aſide.</stage> How do you, Mr. <hi>Leftwell?</hi> Are you reſolv'd to be Married to Mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>No, I'm reſolv'd to ſee whether I ſhall live, or dye, firſt, by your favour.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Some body knocks.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Faith, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> I'm afraid, now my Uncle's gone, they
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:56777:36"/>are come to kill you; theſe people knock with fury: heark, they knock again. Look out at the Window, <hi>Betty,</hi> and bring us word who 'tis, before you let 'em in.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I'le run, Madam.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Mrs. <hi>Fickle,</hi> if I have any heart, 'tis juſt now in my Mouth. For I feel a ſoft thing tumbling between my tongue and my teeth.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>O me, Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> 'tis Mr. <hi>Friendly,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Lovewell;</hi> what will you do?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Dear <hi>Betty,</hi> put me into any place to preſerve me. O, quickly, they'le get in elſe, before I can hide my ſelf.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Come along with me, I'le lock you into the Larder; come, come.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> I proteſt, if thou ſav'ſt me this time, I'le have thee, and let thy Miſtreſs alone.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Hee's ſafe enough.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>I've lockt up the logger-head, now I'le let them in.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exit</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Do, <hi>Betty.</hi> Couſin, put on your Scarf, and fit your ſelf for the March; delayes are dangerous.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I am ready, my dear Girle; give me thy hand. I vow, I can but think, how ſimply we ſhall look, when we come to night to lye with our Lovers.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Thou art the maddeſt Wench that e're wore Petticoat: how ſhould we look, think you?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Lovewell, Friendly, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>My dear <hi>Leticia;</hi> your generous love has laid ſo many obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gations on me, that nothing but the Service of an Age can ſeem a Tithe of ſatisfaction. Which to be paid —</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, forbear your Complements at preſent, and let's make haſte to carry on the work we come about.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Bravely propos'd, my pretty Miſtreſs; if they lye lingring longer, wee'le away, and laugh at them. What doſt thou mean, <hi>Ned?</hi> to be (at this haſty time) telling thy Miſtreſs, in blanck verſe, that which ſhe has been ſatisfy'd in theſe ſix Moneths; how much you love her, and how much ſhe's more than you deſerve; why, ſhe knows both the one, and the other.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="65" facs="tcp:56777:36"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Let.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, their advice at this time is not much amiſs; therefore let's make haſte.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> is the Coaſt clear?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>There's none but the Old Chare-Woman in the Houſe; and ſhe's aſleep in the Chimney Corner.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>I believe Mr. <hi>Leftwell</hi> will make a foul Larder; ſhall we leave him under lock and key?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Hang him, I'le leave the Key in the door, that the next that comes may let him out.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <div n="4" type="scene">
                  <head>Scena quarta.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, <hi>and</hi> Moſes, <hi>with Servants, at Juſtice</hi> Frump's <hi>Houſe;</hi> Frump, <hi>and</hi> Stingey.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pet.</speaker>
                     <p>Mr. Juſtice, 'tis intollerable; a Man muſt ſtand an hour, or two, hearing you talk Non-ſence, inſtead of Law, to delay the time, when a Perſon comes to you in haſte, upon ſo great an occaſion as this is, a matter of life and death.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Stingey,</hi> make him a Warrant; but, Sir, a Warrant that is made upon life and death by a Juſtice of Peace cannot be had for leſs than a Crown; if you will be at the price of it, my Man will make it you. Sir, 'tis nothing to me, the Money comes into his Pocket; I proteſt, I don't deſire a farthing of you, not I.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I don't value a Crown, as worth a thought; but I have been a Juſtice my ſelf, and never heard of ſuch a thing as this.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>I grant you, Sir, not by a Juſtice of <hi>London,</hi> but alwayes by a Juſtice of Peace of <hi>Middleſen.</hi> My Man, Sir, knows the Law, as well as moſt do; and he ſhall ſwear it, if you deſire to hear him.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>He won't, ſure. I'le give him ten ſhillings for the Warrant, if he will.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Sir, give me the Book.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Offers to ſwear.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Hold, Sir, here's a Crown for your Warrant; I would not for a World be ſo inſtrumental in thy deſtruction. God b'ye, Sir; I believe you have kept me ſo long, I have loſt my opportunity.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Exeunt</hi> Pett, <hi>and Servants.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Pay me for my part, <hi>Stingey;</hi> I ought to have ſix pence more than you; for indeed, there is no ſuch price upon any War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Sting.</speaker>
                     <p>That I know, therefore I offer'd to ſwear it, whereas you
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:56777:37"/>only told him ſo; that the Gentleman might be ſatisfy'd.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Frump.</speaker>
                     <p>Give me half a Crown then; and take your Hat, and fetch a quart of Ale for your Miſtreſs out of your Money.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt.</stage>
               </div>
               <div type="scene">
                  <head>Scena Ultima.</head>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Pett, <hi>and Servants.</hi>
                  </stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What, hoe! Daughter, Niece, <hi>Betty!</hi> where are theſe Girles? What, would they offer to go out, and leave the Houſe empty? Go ſome of you, and ſee if you can find them. This idle Juſtice keeping me ſo long, has made me miſs him; but I ſuppoſe, Mr. <hi>Lovewell</hi> will at Night inform me where I may have them. What, have you found them?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Enter Servant.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Serv.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Sir; nor any body, but the old Woman aſleep in the Kitchin Chimney.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What ſhould become of them, and Mr. <hi>Leftwell?</hi> There can be no trick put upon me, forſure they're all together.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>within.</hi> I'm here, Sir; is the Houſe clear? Is there no dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>Prethee, where art, Man?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I am here in ſome place, I don't know what you call it; but 'tis where the cold Meat, and the Kitchin-ſtuff ſtands.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What, are you lockt in the Larder?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>I, Sir, the Larder; <hi>Betty</hi> lockt me in two hours ago; I thank her, ſhe ſav'd my life by't; but now I hope you'le let me out</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Moſes,</hi> unlock the door.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Leftwell.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Father, we have been in ſuch a fright ſince you went; you were no ſooner gone, but comes <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> and <hi>Franck Friendly,</hi> with a full Reſolution to kill me, but <hi>Betty</hi> ſav'd my life. I heard them carry away your Couſin and your Daughter; whom, I believe verily they'le kill for my ſake; and that will be a ſad thing: but better them, than I.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>This was a trick, a deſign; I find it now too late.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter to them,</hi> Lovewell, Leticia, Friendly, Fickle, Runwell, <hi>and</hi> Betty.</stage>
                  <p>Sir, I was ſending after you; 'tis well you have brought my Family home again.</p>
                  <pb n="67" facs="tcp:56777:37"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>With all Humility we beg your Bleſſing, as your Son and Daughter.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Ned Lovewell,</hi> I'faith, I'm glad thou haſt got her; now you will let me live at quiet, I hope, and I'le forgive you all the Money I lent you. I'le ee'ne ſtrike in with <hi>Betty.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>What, have you got my Daughter there? If you have an Eſtate to keep her, 'tis well; you ſhall have none of me: therefore get you out of my ſight.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, your Sentence is very ſevere; will you pleaſe but to hear me.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Sir, I have heard and ſeen too much of you already; but there's your way out, and you may take your Lady with you, for ſhe ſhall ne're come here again.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>Pray, Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> before you go, will you hear me; my Uncle can't hinder me of my Fortune, part of which is at your Service.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>No, Goſſip, it ſhall ne're be ſaid, that my Daughter was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holden to you for her maintenance. Mr. <hi>Lovewell,</hi> I know you're a Gentleman, and I find you're Ingenious; but as you have no Eſtate, if I could have hinder'd it, you ſhould not have Marry'd her; but I will be ſatisfi'd, ſince I ſee 'tis decreed: I am imform'd too, you have behav'd your ſelf handſomly, and honeſtly, and in that believe my Daughter not quite caſt away. My Bleſſing be upon you both; and I'm apt to believe you'le uſe her well, which I doubt whether <hi>Leftwell</hi> would have done. Couſin, I wiſh you joy; your Portion ſhall be paid you when you pleaſe; and if you learn to be thrifty, you may be happy.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>May Heaven, Sir, reward your kindneſs with continual joy; and may I live no longer than that day when I forget to pay you moſt obedient Service.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Sir, I hope in a little time to let you ſee the Fruits of our labour, and am reſolv'd to make you a great Uncle, as ſoon as my Friend <hi>Lovewell</hi> ſhall a Grand-ſire.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Fick.</speaker>
                     <p>O, Sir, theſe liberal promiſers are alwayes ſhort pay-maſters.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>How do you intend to diſpoſe of your ſelf Mr. <hi>Leftwell,</hi> after your great fright?</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Why, I deſire you'de give me leave to Marry your Maid; a Man may have her without danger of being Murder'd, and I have alwayes had a mind to her.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>
                        <hi>Betty,</hi> come hither, give me your hand, I'le make the Match; it ſhall be done to Morrow Morning.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <pb n="68" facs="tcp:56777:38"/>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Betty.</speaker>
                     <p>Now my Miſtreſs is provided for, I begin to love my ſelf ſo well, that I cannot find in my heart to refuſe a good Fortune, though it come by a Fool; whom I believe I can baſte into ſubmiſſion.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <p>Sir, it ſhall be as you command.</p>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Run.</speaker>
                     <p>I'm not a whit ſorry I ha' loſt my Miſtreſs, ſince I ſee ſhe's better provided; neither will I deſpair of making my Fortune by her favour, out of this Aſſe.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Aſide.</stage>
                  <stage>
                     <hi>Enter</hi> Faithfull.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Gentlemen, and Ladies, your Servant; hearing that all things and parties are agreed, I've brought ſome Friends of mine that reſolve to give you a Song and a Dance.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Honeſt <hi>Tom,</hi> 'tis kindly done; and they will, I believe, be very acceptable to all the good Company; but wee'le Dance our ſelves, if your Friends, as you call them, will but ſtrike up. I wiſh thou hadſt a Miſtreſs too, to make thy happineſs equal ours.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>Mine wants but little on't; for I'm reſolv'd to live as well as you: now you two are rich, I'le ne're be poor.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>Thou art ours for ever, <hi>Tom.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <p>But he ſhould keep his Hands clean, then.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Faith.</speaker>
                     <p>What, won't Marriage tame you? Still abuſive? I muſt ſtop your Mouths with Muſick.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Muſick playes, and Dance.</stage>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Pett.</speaker>
                     <p>All excellent good, i'faith; very good indeed: pray, Son, and Nephew, walk in, and leade your Wives to Supper, for it grows near that time; for <hi>Betty</hi>'s ſake, you ſhall be welcome too, Mr. <hi>Left<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>well.</hi>
                     </p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Left.</speaker>
                     <p>Nay, I care not for whoſe ſake it is; ſo I have but enough, I ſhall be very well ſatisfy'd. Come, Sweeting.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Friend.</speaker>
                     <p>If we had been unhappy in the loſs of our Miſtreſſes now, I ſhould have grown almoſt out of love with Honeſty.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <speaker>Love.</speaker>
                     <lg>
                        <l>O, there's nothing like it.</l>
                        <l>Let all that would do ill be rul'd by me;</l>
                        <l>For by this Preſident you plainly ſee</l>
                        <l>Fate ſtill reſerves rewards for Honeſty.</l>
                     </lg>
                  </sp>
                  <stage>Exeunt omnes.</stage>
               </div>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
            <div type="epilogue">
               <pb facs="tcp:56777:38"/>
               <head>EPILOGUE.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>NOw, Gallants, your reſult; we fain would know</l>
                  <l>Whether you Judge it fit to live, or no:</l>
                  <l>This truth wee'le ſay, to mitigate its Crime,</l>
                  <l>It is his firſt; made in a fortnight's time.</l>
                  <l>A Critick, for that Reaſon, ought to give,</l>
                  <l>If not a Pardon, ſurely, a Reprieve.</l>
                  <l>'Twould be high Tyranny for to inveigh,</l>
                  <l>In cruel terms, againſt an Infant Play.</l>
                  <l>But if your Laws all mercy do deny;</l>
                  <l>Hee's ſure to have relief in equity:</l>
                  <l>He appeals thither, as his proper Sphear,</l>
                  <l>Nor can he be compelled to appear</l>
                  <l>In any other Court; but could he by perſwaſions draw</l>
                  <l>You to be kind in equity and Law;</l>
                  <l>And ſee it ſign'd with all your hands, hee'le be,</l>
                  <l>Though now but weak, your's in Maturity.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
